<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Egmont Mika</title>
    <link>http://egmontmika.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Egmont Mika</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2015 06:39:19 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://egmontmika.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s Your Response to Terror?</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/how-do-you-respond-to-terror/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2015 06:39:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/how-do-you-respond-to-terror/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Paris, November 13th, 2015 !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overwhelmed and horrified by what happened that night, I asked myself, &lt;em&gt;What is my response to all those terror attacks in recent years, not only in the Middle East and in places “far away”, but also increasingly in Europe?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Will the horror stay with me and eventually leave me in a constant state of fear? Will it affect my attitude towards the world and the people around me, towards Muslims in general as well as towards my Muslim friends, colleagues, students and neighbours?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And will it possibly lead me to a reaction that ultimately feeds into a culture of resentment, distrust and fear?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing is for sure, if I let fear grip me, then the attacks have accomplished their purpose in me and the terrorists have won the victory!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This shall never happen!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, there is another possible response.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘Eagles of Death Metal’, the band that played at Bataclan that night, made the following statement, issued in &lt;em&gt;The Guardian&lt;/em&gt; on November 18th:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Although bonded in grief with the victims, the fans, the families, the citizens of Paris, and all those affected by terrorism, we are proud to stand together, with our new family, now united by a common goal of love and compassion.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This view opens up for a better response and reminds me of the mission we have as followers of Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You and I may not be able to stop terrorism and solve all the problems connected to it. However, we can remain the masters of our minds and our faith, guard our feelings and attitudes, care for each other, build trust relationships and cultivate community - Muslims included.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overcoming fear by practicing love and true humanity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taking action for a better world.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Walking the Bumpy Road</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/walking-the-bumpy-road/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2015 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/walking-the-bumpy-road/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are you looking for a safe and comfortable road to travel on?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, following Jesus might not be the right choice for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jesus never invited anyone to a safe journey. Neither did his Father. The Bible is filled with stories about men and women who knew God and faithfully followed him on a rather bumpy road with many potholes, detours and dangers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just think of Abraham, Joseph, Moses, Elijah, David, Isaiah, Jeremiah, Jesus, Paul… Their lives were characterized by dangers, hardship, risks, threats, agonies and persecution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jesus was one of them, and he didn’t promise his followers anything different from what he experienced. Least of all security and comfort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, this seems to be what millions of his followers daily pray for and expect for their lives. And churches do their best to make Christianity appear a pleasant experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And in case we let Sunday morning performances be the foremost expression of what it means to follow Jesus, this is what we communicate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, by filtering out the hardship, the pain, the struggle, the risks, the drop-backs, the sweat and the dirt of everyday life, we may end up reducing discipleship to a nice Sunday morning smile. That kind of religion will never stand the test of credibility. Neither the test of authenticity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, if we intentionally face those trials, the hardship and the discomfort, and not only try but actually overcome by strengthening our faith, putting our spiritual weapons into practice and standing side by side as brothers and sisters, trusting the Lord to give us a victory, we make an astonishing discovery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We then find out that He is with us right there walking alongside with us, leading us through every hardship and towards our destiny. And we discover that this bumpy and tiresome road we are walking on actually is the road of our calling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The road where His grace becomes most visible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What a blessing!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your Great Work</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/your-great-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2015 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/your-great-work/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Great work doesn’t come out of nowhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it’s not only a privilege for the talented.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Usually great work results from someone working hard and trying over and over again, failing included - many times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover, it&amp;rsquo;s risky.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s risky before you get started, and it&amp;rsquo;s risky all the way through until it&amp;rsquo;s finished. It can cost you everything; your time, your sleep, your comfort, your money, your reputation - and your pride.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Great work makes you humble.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Great work isn’t always recognized as such from the beginning. And you often don&amp;rsquo;t see its greatness during the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those who don’t have the faith, it really doesn’t look that great. They just can’t imagine that you are building a cathedral. What they see is the sand you are shoveling; and they notice the dirt, the sweat and the pain it causes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Raising children is very much like that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Changing diapers just doesn&amp;rsquo;t feel that glorious. And coping with a teenager’s mood doesn’t always look like a great success. Nevertheless, it&amp;rsquo;s great work! No matter what you feel during the process and no matter how many times you fail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s great, as long as you carry on faithfully, day by day, year in year out. The time will come when you and even others will see the result of your labour. One day your cathedral will be completed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, raising children is far greater than building a cathedral.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feeling Like a Failure?</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/feeling-like-a-failure/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2015 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/feeling-like-a-failure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Having failed isn&amp;rsquo;t the same as feeling like a failure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feeling like a failure can be much worse than the actual failure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A failure in itself is just an event, not a feeling. It&amp;rsquo;s something specific that happened to you at a specific time in a specific place. Like you didn’t pass the test, couldn’t keep your promise, missed your flight, lost your credit card, or made a foolish comment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A failure can be dealt with successfully in basically three ways&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can repair the damage. There is no use crying over spilt milk. You know what to do, so just do it. Often a simple excuse is good enough.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can’t repair the damage, but you definitely can learn from it. Notorious late comers can actually stop blaming the circumstances and instead admit their failure, go to the bottom of their issue and take practical steps to change their habit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can ignore it. If you just missed an opportunity, there isn’t much that can be done. No use of grieving. It may be emotionally challenging and you may have to pay a price, but so what? You must leave it behind you and carry on.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not always easy to handle a failure, but most failures can be dealt with in a rational way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s much harder to cope with feelings. Feelings can be irrational.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feeling like a failure has very little to do with actually failing. You can fail a thousand times without necessarily feeling like a failure. On the other hand, you can even feel like a failure in the face of obvious success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feeling like a failure isn’t based on what has occurred, but on our thinking. On the story we tell ourselves or what others tell us about ourselves. Such a story works like a prophecy. Once you believe it, you will try to prove it and find evidence for it. For sure, you will always find what you are looking for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you feel discriminated, neglected, looked down at, hated or felt sorry for, rest assured they have their origin in patterns of thoughts… in your story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, if you want to protect yourself and stop feeling like a failure, there are a few essential steps you can take:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Stop meditating on your false story. Throw it out of your mind and refuse to let it settle there again, whenever those thoughts show up. Remember that you are the master of your mind.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Stop engaging with the false assumption that in order to stop feeling like a failure you’ll have to succeed. You don&amp;rsquo;t. You can get rid of that feeling without a single success.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Instead, start meditating on another story, based on the story that Jesus gave us: ”You are a child of God, beautifully made, loved, forgiven and accepted, created for a divine purpose, destined to be a blessing…&amp;rdquo; Let your Father in heaven determine who you are and what you are.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you choose the latter and start building your faith on His story, for sure, your feelings will follow and you will be healed and restored.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; The decision is yours.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your Precious Failures</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/your-precious-failures/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2015 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/your-precious-failures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nobody likes failures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, failures are more precious than most of us are inclined to think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, they can become stepping stones towards our final success. Don’t get me wrong, a failure really is a failure, not a success. It&amp;rsquo;s ugly, discouraging, accusing, threatening, judging! However&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A failure doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to be the final word spoken. The crucial question is, what do you do with it? What comes next?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think of Thomas Edison. Holding as many as 1093 patents in the United States, and in addition many patents in the United Kingdom, France, and Germany, he probably was one of the most prolific inventors of all times. Edison became famous not only for the widespread impact of his inventions, but also for his unbroken decisiveness to never give up. It is said that before succeeding with his first well-functioning light bulb in 1879, he went through around 2000 failures. When during the time of his endless struggles being asked, why he wouldn’t give up such a meaningless endeavor, he gave his well-known answer. ”It’s not a failure at all”, he said, ”I just found 2000 ways of how not to make a light bulb”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inventions are made when someone thinks outside the box and tries to accomplish something that others call impossible, or at least meaningless, and uses every failure as a stepping stone for still another try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, our problem is that we are stuck inside the box and all we can do is think inside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, how do you manage to think on the outside? What then makes individuals finally free themselves from the bonds of the well-known and secure paths of thought, risk a failure and jump the leap? How do you accomplish such a feat?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many times, it’s through a deep crisis caused by a failure. Sometimes, it’s out of pure desperation. You are stuck and can&amp;rsquo;t see any way out. You hit the bottom and have nothing to lose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is when you are ready to stretch beyond what seems possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seen that way, failures are the condition in which creativity is ignited. They are the soil out of which success springs forth, but only for those who stop mourning and lamenting and decide to try again and go on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Judas didn’t have to end up in a tragedy. That was his own decision, his own self-made judgement. As Jesus restored Peter, I am sure he was ready to even forgive Judas and open up a new life for him, a life of peace and freedom way beyond his failure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how do you think about your recent failure? What’s your decision? Are you ready to welcome and embrace it and learn from it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And open a new and unexpected door.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Geoffrey:&lt;/em&gt;  Thank you Egmont! This is true and I have been in failures many times, and I have seen the hand of God in the end of it. The worst part was when I was laughed at, but I was deeply convicted that God my heavenly father will turn it up for his glory. Thanks again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reply:&lt;/em&gt; Thank you, Geoff! You are right. The Lord is a master of turning things round. We just need to wait.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Full-Time, Part-Time or Spare-Time Ministry?</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/full-time%20or%20part-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 06:39:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/full-time%20or%20part-time/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a disciple of Jesus, do you have a full-time or a part-time ministry?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or is yours &amp;ldquo;only&amp;rdquo; spare-time?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No matter what your answer is, following Jesus is neither one. If you are his disciple, you are what you are twenty-four hours a day, seven days a week. That’s neither full-time nor part-time nor spare-time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;all-the-time!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason for that? Discipleship isn’t based on a service, a duty or a program. It&amp;rsquo;s neither an employment nor a hobby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Discipleship is a relationship - your relationship with Jesus. And as his disciple you are a child of God; that’s a position, and again a relationship. Everything you do is done within that relationship and can be seen as an expression of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, churches and denominations offer employments, full-time or part-time. And they engage volunteers in their spare-time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All these workers have their specific responsibilities and duties. They follow the instructions, meet people&amp;rsquo;s needs, and try to make everyone happy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On top of that, they probably have an idea of listening to the Lord and try to follow him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doing both of these doesn&amp;rsquo;t always work out so well. Following Jesus and fulfilling the requirements for an employee or volunteer aren’t automatically the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following Jesus isn&amp;rsquo;t the same as building an organization or pleasing the people around you. If it works out for you, that&amp;rsquo;s fine. As long as it lasts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At worst, you may feel like having to serve two masters, which can lead to conflict, frustration and stress, and sometimes even burn-out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jesus worked hard, yet never seemed to get any of these symptoms. Is it, because he only served one master and never submitted to people’s expectations?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus, he was free to wholeheartedly listen to the Spirit and obey the One who had sent him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any-time. All-the-time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are You a Spiritual Leader?</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/are-you-a-spiritual-leader/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2015 06:39:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/are-you-a-spiritual-leader/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Following Jesus rubs off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a disciple of Jesus, you influence your environment and the people around you. Discipleship often develops into leadership.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a different kind of leadership, though. Different from what most people would expect. Often lacking the most typical characteristics that you usually associate with leadership, like power, position, title, status, money, popularity, image, good looks, high IQ, education, or whatever else impresses on people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s an up-side-down leadership. It&amp;rsquo;s built on servanthood and qualities like humility, honesty and integrity. Like trustworthiness, reliability and morality. And faithfulness and wisdom. And love. And the fear of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In short, it&amp;rsquo;s spiritual leadership.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;True spiritual leadership is based on discipleship, that is, on being a disciple of Jesus. Discipleship comes first, spiritual leadership emerges from there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can’t lead another person along a spiritual path without first having walked that path yourself. And you can’t lead that person into a fruitful disciple relationship without being a disciple yourself. The quality of your leadership depends uttermost on the quality of your discipleship. You cannot lead a disciple beyond your own level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, are you looking for a spiritual leader? Then, have a closer look at his or her discipleship. Leaders in formal positions are not necessarily fruitful disciples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, fruitful disciples can naturally develop into spiritual leaders, independently of any formal position.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might be one of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;comments:4de4065ea1f1f9d60973d0fdd5cda222&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Comments&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amelie&lt;/strong&gt; - LOVE IT!
I always thought I needed more of the typical leadership qualities in order to be a great leader, but I found out that there are people around me that I can disciple. That makes being a leader so easy and it comes so natural.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Susan&lt;/strong&gt; - I am begining to see this more and more. Strange that it should take so long for me to arrive at this conclusion&amp;hellip;Truly desire to walk this path with any who sincerely wants to join. :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Share a Meal</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/share-a-meal/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2015 06:39:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/share-a-meal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hospitality is an expression of God’s character.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our Lord is a welcoming God. He is generous, nourishing, lavish, joyful…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He is hospitable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this is what we are communicating to others when being hospital. It’s as easy as sharing a meal with a friend, a collegue, a neighbor, or a stranger. Or why not a beggar! God is indiscriminate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He is including.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your meal doesn’t have to be fancy; don’t let it be exclusive. There is no need to impress on anyone. Just share what you have, it may be abundant or little, a three-course dinner or a glas of water. Or a piece of chocolate or a banana. Just act hospitable according to the situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actually, it’s not so much about the food, but about your attitude, what people sense when they are together with you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hospitality is an expression of grace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You give people an experience of being accepted, respected, appreciated and honored. A sense of belonging without having to qualify or to argue. It breaks the power of fear and alienation and prejudice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s an expression of freedom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You create an environment of generosity, free from control and free from guilt and accusations. Also free from the need to impress and pretend. Allowing people to be who they are. Giving them your love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Creating community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Creating an experience of how God is.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mentorship - Respect, Freedom and Trust</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/respect-freedom-and-trust/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2015 06:39:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/respect-freedom-and-trust/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Definition&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Jesus commanded his disciples to go out and make disciples, they understood this as building a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;master-disciple&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; relationship. The apostle Paul translated it into his greco-roman world by instead talking about a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;father-son&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; relationship. Today, we often use the term &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;mentorship&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, it&amp;rsquo;s the same content, the same mission. It&amp;rsquo;s the mission that Jesus gave us.This is how I use this term in my blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mentorship - Respect, Freedom and Trust&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mentorship requires trust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And trust presupposes respect and freedom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a mentor this means respecting another person’s background and personality, her opinion, taste, religion, or whatever she brings along. Also her negative sides. It’s possible to show respect without necessarily agreeing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, it means respecting that person’s decisions.  Granting her the freedom to live her life and follow her own preferences. This includes the freedom to say “yes” or “no” to Jesus, and  also to you as her mentor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Respect and freedom - these are the preconditions, but finally it’s all about trust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trust is a relationship. You can’t buy it, neither do you get it by begging or arguing or manipulating. And you never build trust by engaging someone in your projects, thus “using” her for your own purposes. There is no such way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trust grows gradually&amp;hellip; You’ll have to build it, patiently and carefully through consistency in action, thought and motives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trust needs to be cultivated, not managed. There is a world of difference between those two.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Respect, freedom and trust - you can see them in Jesus’ way of meeting people, as three expressions of his love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As his disciples and communicators of that love,  we can never depart from those three. If we ignore any of them, we lose our mentor relationship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, acting Jesus-like means in this context:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Showing respect, even when disrespected&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Granting freedom,  even when controlled, manipulated or threatened.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Building trust, even when undeserved.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can start out with any acquaintance, on any level of relationship. Sometimes, though, you&amp;rsquo;ll have to start from scratch. It isn’t always easy.  People aren’t easy. For you as a mentor, it’s an investment into another person’s life. An investment of your love, time and energy, although with no guarantees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However when successful, it’s an investment that produces good fruit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the way to eternity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Give to the Lord...</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/give-to-the-lord/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2015 06:39:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/give-to-the-lord/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Give to the Lord what he is asking you for!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No one is born as a disciple of Jesus, far less a disciple maker. Yet, this is what Jesus wants us to be, a disciple and a disciple maker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Accordingly, somewhere along the road, there must be a turning point, or a new start. For every one of us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We may argue that we are not gifted like evangelist so and so or pastor so and so…, but that’s not the point! They do it their way, and we are asked to do it our way. There is no one else on the planet who can do it just like you and me, and fill the place that only you and I can fill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we don’t show up, the Kingdom will lack some important and unique workers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We may say that we are decent and regular church goers. We have attended hundreds or even thousands of worship services, dozens of bible studies and we are supporting one or several ministries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s all quite impressive and good&amp;hellip; however, being a disciple and making a disciple has little to do with all this. Why did Jesus in his great commission not even mention all these things that today form our Christian culture and keep us busy, week after week?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The question then to ask is: What are we doing? Are we disciple makers?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And by that I am not referring to the success we have achieved&amp;hellip;. we must leave that part up to the Lord. All we need to worry about is: whether we are engaging in such a task or not?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I trust this summer vacation will give us time to reflect on this question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Discipleship is not a selfish act. It’s a service to the world and to every human soul. We can’t cheat the Lord. But let us not cheat ourselves. And let us also not cheat humanity of our contribution. Instead, let us give each other and the world what we’ve got.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And to the Lord what he is asking us for!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How You Can Learn Patience</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/how-you-can-learn-patience/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2015 06:39:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/how-you-can-learn-patience/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;”I want patience, and I want it right NOW!!!”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The more you yell, the more you’ll miss it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No one is born with patience, in fact, the opposite is true. And there is no short-cut to get it. No button to push, no recipe to follow, no course to attend. It’s nothing money can buy…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Patience is learned the hard way. Over time, and through suffering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By suffering the pain of waiting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;God doesn’t seem to have a problem with it. He is the Master of patience. He can wait. For days and weeks and months and years, and if necessary, a few thousand of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Patience is so much part of his character that we can’t even think of him as not being patient. Being patient with &lt;em&gt;us&lt;/em&gt;, of course!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We like that idea, yet, it’s not the end of the story. Even in this respect, he wants us to become more like him, share his godly character, and produce some good fruit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, if this is his will for you and me, and if this is what we really want, why don’t we go for it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome every opportunity to train patience and get a little closer to our goal. Or even look out for these opportunities and rejoice whenever we find one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every day you can simply find some situation that makes you wait.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then train yourself in the godly character of being patient. Suffer a little with that purpose in mind…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And enjoy it!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding Simplicity</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/finding-simplicity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2015 06:39:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/finding-simplicity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Simplicity isn’t the same as poverty. Poverty is a curse, simplicity is an accomplishment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The accomplishment of the wise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simplicity is obtainable. Everyone can achieve it, but not everyone will.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you turn around and start following Jesus, many things will turn simpler for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This doesn’t mean that you flee from the complexity of life. Rather, you face and embrace it, and then simplify by making active choices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You structure your hours and plan your activities in order to follow your calling and accomplish an aim. You bring your will in line with that aim, and faithfully and diligently stick to your decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This changes your life and simplifies it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll know what time to get up and what time to go to bed. You’ll know what to engage in and what to exclude. You’ll know what kind of food you feed yourself with, even mentally and spiritually, what you want to read, listen to and look at.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And you consciously keep away from distractions. You practice mental hygiene.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of all, you’ll change your attitude. You’ll take away your pride, insecurities and self-concerns, opening your view for the needs of others. That will save you from a lot of self-made problems. It simplifies it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Up to your turning point, you allow distractions to fill your life. You don’t want to miss anything. Your days can be filled to the bursting point, but leave you heartbreakingly empty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that turning point, this will be fundamentally different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, your life is filled with a purpose and you are on your way. You can afford to miss a thousand things without loosing anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And stay simple!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overcoming Fear</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/overcoming-fear/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2015 06:39:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/overcoming-fear/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The enemy of faith is fear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fearing sickness, death and final judgement, fearing failure… Fearing what others might think of me, fearing their rejection. Or their complacency. Or fearing my boss, my bills, the weather or just anything that might happen in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we meet God’s grace, the undercurrent of our life is fear. Fear makes us worry. It makes us live in a state of denial. Denying who we really are. Denying our calling. Denying that small voice in our heart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Denying the presence of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fear makes us run away into some sort of addiction or distraction. Or into a shadow career, trying to become someone or achieve something that will give us acknowledgment and security and finally somehow wipe out the fear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I experienced God’s grace and started following Jesus, this situation changed. Fear didn’t just disappear, though, but I stopped fleeing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I stopped denying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I turned around and started facing it. Using my newfound weapon, the knowledge of being accepted, forgiven, and loved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trusting God and his victory. Overcoming fear.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s the Perfect Church?</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/what%27s-the-perfect-church/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2015 06:39:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/what%27s-the-perfect-church/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There is no such thing as a perfect church. Most Christians agree on that!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why then does it shock us when something happens in the church that absolutely should not have happened? Yes, of course, it’s okay if it happens in the world, but in the church, among the saints?!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Disgusting! How could this be!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But wait a minute! Why are we contradicting ourselves? In one breath we say the church isn’t perfect, and at the same time we act offended by its imperfections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Isn’t it, because we have an idea of what the church “is” or really “should be”, and we expect it to match up to that picture?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the church fails. &lt;em&gt;We&lt;/em&gt; fail… Again and again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, where does that picture of the unfailing church come from?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do we get it from the Bible and the first church? Or is it just our own idealized, romantic view, our illusion of the church?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t think that this is how Jesus viewed his first twelve disciples. They were anything but perfect. And it’s not the picture we get of the first church in Jerusalem either. And definitely not the churches that Paul wrote to!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Would the Early Church ever have matched up to our expectations?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing is for sure, Jesus doesn’t get nervous when looking at our failures. Obviously, he knew from the beginning what kind of people we are, and must have taken that into account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, he commanded us to forgive each other. And with that he is not willing to compromise, because it is the only way we can proceed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover, he gave us the mandate to forgive in his name, by his grace. This is powerful! This changes everything!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And in his sight, that makes us truly ‘perfect’.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Faith Isn&#39;t Religion</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/faith-isn%27t-religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 06:39:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/faith-isn%27t-religion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Following Jesus calls for faith.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, faith and religion aren’t the same. Faith isn’t religion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t confuse the two!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Typically, religion is made up of two components: There is a set of statements about what a group of people, an organization, a movement, or a society consider to be true. And there are rules, rituals and traditions to follow, as applications of these truths.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Faith, however, is beyond those things. It’s originated in another realm… it springs forth out of your spirit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Faith is your genuine trust in God, including your actions based on that trust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Faith cannot be institutional or traditional. It’s always personal, and always fresh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s rooted deep inside of you, generating qualities such as confidence, motivation, vision, courage, mental strength, patience, endurance… Faith is the ultimate motor of your actions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Religion is great as long as it provides a positive, supporting environment for that faith. At its best, it amplifies your faith. Then, religion may work out for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, that’s not always the case. As you develop spiritually, the opposite can become true. In fact, at some point, religion can hinder your faith. Even kill it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While faith lets you imagine what could be possible and encourages you to act on that imagination, take risks, explore and conquer, religion reinforces the status-quo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Religion makes you fit in, not stand out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Religion is like a blanket overlaid on top of your faith. As long as you accept its limits or don’t ever recognize them, you feel fine under that blanket and enjoy whatever it offers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, for those who want to take initiative and practice an amount of freedom that is beyond those limits, the blanket turns into an iron ceiling, mentally and spiritually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you reach that point, you have only two options: stay, adapt to the status quo and let it limit your faith, or leave.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case you are alive enough to leave, people may wonder whether you lost your faith. Probably, rather the opposite is true, though. Stepping out can be the very consequence of your faith. You leave because your faith requires it. What you leave is not your faith, but just a certain temporary religious, social or cultural expression of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leaving is never a convenient step. It’s painful, because you’ll have to leave a familiar, secure and confirming environment. It’s like climbing an unknown mountain. From time to time, it’s necessary, though, if you want to grow as a disciple and become more fruitful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To others it may look foolish, or like a heresy or a betrayal. Or they may even envy you but decide to stay, because the price seems too high.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You, however, are ready.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>