<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Recent Content on Egmont Mika </title>
      <generator uri="https://hugo.spf13.com">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://egmontmika.com/index.xml</link>
    <language>en-US</language>
    
    
    <updated>Sat, 17 Jan 2015 22:10:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/about</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2015 22:10:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/about</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I am Egmont Mika, a teacher and a mentor, passionate about God and people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Residence: Uppsala, Sweden
 / Family: Wife Åsa, five children, six grandchildren / Profession: Teacher of Art and German Language in Uppsala, Sweden / Discipleship: Follower of Jesus, mentor, bible teacher, housechurch leader&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;The Mission&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This blog is based on Jesus&amp;rsquo; commission, Go out and make disciples of all nations.
Here, I am jotting down my personal thoughts on what it means to genuinely follow Jesus in every day living, to fulfill his mission and to form authentic communities of disciples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;The People&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further, I am led by the conviction that discipleship is a calling for every believer - not only for professionals and in an institutional setting - and that every disciple of Jesus is authorized to lead others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;The Method&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe that this is best done through personal mentorship from person to person, one on one and one by one, and in connection with a small community or family of disciples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am regarding this method as the method that Jesus practiced himself when training his first disciples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And inspite of impressive results of both megachurches and worldwide denominations, I still regard one-on-one mentorship in combination with a small community as the most effective method for disciple making, no matter if inside or outside any institutional frame.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_3&#34;&gt;The Objective&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Probably, this is the method that is best suited to create movements of disciples in any social, cultural and geographical context, and with only a minimum of material resources required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The objective is to fulfill the vision that Jesus gave us, to let the gospel go viral and touch every human heart around the globe.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/contact</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2015 22:11:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/contact</guid>
      <description>&lt;iframe height=&#34;517&#34; allowTransparency=&#34;true&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; style=&#34;width:100%;border:none&#34;  src=&#34;https://enegmontmika.wufoo.com/embed/z1ivn2t40wn1kon/&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://enegmontmika.wufoo.com/forms/z1ivn2t40wn1kon/&#34;&gt;Fill out the contact form!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Jesus Community</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/a-jesus-community</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2015 03:01:45 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/a-jesus-community</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You don&amp;rsquo;t have to be a pastor in order to make a disciple of Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And you don&amp;rsquo;t need to be an apostle or prophet, or an appointed church leader or church planter in order to form a community of disciples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My wife and I do not hold any of these offices and we never formally “started a church”. In fact, we never attempted to.
However, there has been an informal community of disciples around us ever since we opened up our family and our home and let others join us in our walk with Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This has been going on for more than 40 years and it still continues: Informal gatherings for meals, worship, bible study, prayer, counselling, working on a project, celebrations, hikes and other outdoor activities, parties, traveling&amp;hellip; and of course, personal mentoring and baptism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of these people have been living with us in our home for a year or two, or just a few months, some of them have been working with us daily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, we never had a membership list, appointed leaders, a board of elders, a budget, a constitution, a statement of faith, a list of core values, a mission statement - neither any conflict, splitting, economical problem, or burned out. And we never had any vision other than the one that Jesus gave his disciples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Probably, most people wouldn&amp;rsquo;t call it a &amp;ldquo;real church”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, there has been a constant flow of new connections, of teaching and modeling, and a building of community. In Jesus&amp;rsquo; name and under the guidance of his Spirit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of those who have been around us during these years now live in other countries and other continents. With some of them we still are in touch, per email, through social media and through actually visiting each other. Flights are cheap nowadays and make it possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This wonderful bunch of people - we may call it community - is both very little and quite large, anything between two or three and nearly a hundred.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s both a local family and a worldwide community. It&amp;rsquo;s well defined by the people who are actually meeting at a certain place and time, but it&amp;rsquo;s also hard to grasp due to its openness and flexibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not a brand, an organisation, a building, or an office, yet, it&amp;rsquo;s not just an idea in our heads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s kept together by Jesus as Lord and by the personal relationships created by him. It&amp;rsquo;s very real and it surely is glorious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a Jesus community.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>