<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Blogs on Egmont Mika </title>
      <generator uri="https://hugo.spf13.com">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/index.xml</link>
    <language>en-US</language>
    
    
    <updated>Thu, 22 Jan 2015 03:01:45 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ranking Jesus&#39; Words</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/ranking-jesus-words</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2015 03:01:45 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/ranking-jesus-words</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Jesus said: “Go and make disciples!” As a disciple of Jesus, how do those words rank on your list?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you think of your work, your spare time, your daily routines, and weekly obligations, including your spiritual engagements and church activities, where on that list would you place your response to Jesus’ words about making disciples?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe you have already made some disciples, or just one, or maybe none. Or maybe you are just about to make one, or planning to. Or have tried and given up, or never tried, but would like to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes our routines, habits and obligations crowd out the most important things in life. And most often our church culture with all its programs, activities and obligations keeps us from caring enough for another person and from taking the time, the effort and the sacrifice that it takes to make a disciple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, whom shall we blame?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No matter how glorious or how lousy you and I may feel about it, this is a new year and today is a new day and along with it comes the freedom for a new decision and a new start. It’s up to you and me how we respond to Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Disciple making isn’t easy for anyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, it’s possible for those who rank it high on their list.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Jesus Community</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/a-jesus-community</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2015 06:39:19 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/a-jesus-community</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It doesn&amp;rsquo;t take an apostle or a prophet, an appointed church leader or a church planter in order to form a simple community of disciples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My wife and I do not hold any of these offices and we never formally started a church. In fact, we never attempted to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, there has been an informal community of disciples around us ever since we opened up our family and our home and let others join us in our walk with Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This has been going on for more than 40 years and it still continues: Informal gatherings for meals, worship, bible study, prayer, counselling, working on a project, celebrations, hikes and other outdoor activities, parties, traveling&amp;hellip; and of course, personal mentoring and baptism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of these people have been living with us in our home for a year or two, or just a few months, some of them have been working with us daily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, we never had a membership list, appointed leaders, a board of elders, a budget, a constitution, a statement of faith, a list of core values, a mission statement - neither any conflict, splitting, economical problem, or burned out. And we never had any vision other than the one that Jesus gave his disciples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Probably, most people wouldn&amp;rsquo;t call it a &amp;ldquo;real church”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, there has been a constant flow of new connections, of teaching and modeling, and a building of community. In Jesus&amp;rsquo; name and under the guidance of his Spirit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of those who have been around us during these years now live in other countries and other continents. With some of them we still are in touch, per email, through social media and through actually visiting each other. Flights are cheap nowadays and make it possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This wonderful bunch of people - we may call it community - is both very little and quite large, anything between two or three and nearly a hundred.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s both a local family and a worldwide community. It&amp;rsquo;s well defined by the people who are actually meeting at a certain place and time, but it&amp;rsquo;s also hard to grasp due to its openness and flexibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not a brand, an organisation, a building, or an office, yet, it&amp;rsquo;s not just an idea in our heads either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s kept together by Jesus as Lord and by the personal relationships created by him. It&amp;rsquo;s very real and it surely is glorious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a Jesus community.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>God&#39;s Family - an Institution?</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/gods-family-an-institution</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2014 06:34:40 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/gods-family-an-institution</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;God wants a family. Yet, man builds him an institution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you a father or a mother? Then imagine what it would feel like, if your children, as they grow up, turned your family into an institution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What would that be like?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Formal membership instead of family relations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Organized meetings and programs at special times of the week instead of common family life&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rented facilities instead of homes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Formal, elected leadership instead of parenthood&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Board meetings instead of family counsel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Democratic voting instead of common agreement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Symbolic, formalistic eating and drinking instead of real meals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tithings, and offerings whenever you come together… (The list goes on.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Honestly, as a father or a mother, would you build your family like that? And as a child or a grandchild, would you like to carry on with that kind of a heritage? Is this what you want to hand on to your own children and grandchildren?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I doubt it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How does the Lord feel about it? Is this how we best express our testimony about him who is our Father and who loves us and cares for us? Is this a true and convincing expression of his kingdom?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, I doubt it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So why are we doing this? Why are we doing this to our Father in heaven, and to each other, and to the ones we disciple, to our spiritual children?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For how long do we want to carry on? For how long do &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt;? – For sure, there is a better way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be a family!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not difficult, and it’s not far away. You can start out with two or three others and right where you are. Any follower of Jesus can take the initiative, or join someone else and contribute. No matter, if inside or outside the institution. You don&amp;rsquo;t need a building or a program or a vision or a name or a constitution or a logo or a budget or a ministry or an office&amp;hellip; And you don&amp;rsquo;t need permission.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It just takes a decision and initiation. Would that be a too hard or adventurous thing to do? What could possibly hinder you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The choice is yours and mine. And also the responsibility.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dare Letting Go!</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/dare-letting-go</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2014 08:46:54 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/dare-letting-go</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Do you want to move forward? Improve something? Make a positive change in your life?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But feel stuck?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you stuck in your past, your job, your debts, your reputation, your weight, your failures, your self-esteem, your salary, your bad experiences&amp;hellip;? Is your spiritual life going in circles with mere religious routines and habits?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s easy to get stuck, and it’s easy to give up and stay where you are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People spend huge amounts of time and money seeking to innovate and upgrade themselves, working to give up something, start something, build something or change something about who they are and what they do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And ultimately fail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reaching a place where you accept failure and stop dreaming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may call it wisdom or realism and try to turn it into a virtue. But, in actuality it is killing you. Killing your dreams, your ambitions, your initiatives, your self-esteem and your joy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; a better way. Change is possible for everyone, including you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Probably, change doesn&amp;rsquo;t come by just doing more of what you are already doing now. Working even harder, faster, longer, and sleeping less isn’t the answer. It simply ruins your health and your family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Neither is it a matter of style or fashion or image cultivation, or of following the trend and trying to be cool. Real, lasting and satisfying change just isn’t accomplished by polishing the surface, but rather by a change on the inside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To begin with, you’ll have to stop racing, stop pushing and stop forcing yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the same is true with the negative counterpart: Stop complaining, stop mourning, stop grieving and stop pitying yourself. Stop resigning. You&amp;rsquo;ll have to realize and acknowledge that whatever brought you to the point where you are now belongs to your past and that you are not obliged to go on with it for still another decade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And no matter how successful your walk has been in the past, maybe you&amp;rsquo;ll have to admit that it finally turned out to be a dead end road for you. It may have been good for a long time, but now it’s not working out anymore. Not good enough. Not for the next five or ten or twenty years of your life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second step would be to let go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t try to save as much of the old as possible. Admitted, there are a lot of good things worth sparing. But, as the saying goes, the good is the enemy of the best. If you want to get anywhere, you can’t keep all the old stuff and let it occupy your space and your freedom, just because it might become useful again some day in the future. You can&amp;rsquo;t save it for eternity anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There has to be some sort of inner capitulation, before you can step out into the new and unknown, the risky and the scary. And the rewarding and satisfying. Into your Father&amp;rsquo;s arms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It often takes a crisis to make us willing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And in fact, every crisis offers an opportunity for positive change. Yet, many never get all the way through to the other side where the new horizon becomes visible and the change possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They just don’t want to give up their security and their convenience. Or their illusion of who they are and what they have accomplished. Or their pride. Or fear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you desperate enough to let go?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are You Quite Normal?</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/are-you-quite-normaly</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2014 06:39:19 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/are-you-quite-normaly</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For being a disciple of Jesus, people may regard you as not being quite normal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what is ”normal”? In relation to what?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It could be many things, like eating breakfast in the morning, working during the day, watching the news in the evening, and sleeping at night. In that respect a disciple of Jesus wouldn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily stick out from the crowd and could be considered quite normal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, let&amp;rsquo;s think of some other more subtle aspects of life. Like for instance, our values, our fears and our desire for security.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It could be considered normal to not want to associate with certain kinds of people, like people from a different stratum of life than ours - the poor, the homeless, the foreigners, the social outcasts, those from another religious group, those who don’t share the same political views like us etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We usually don&amp;rsquo;t want to get involved with someone too different from ourselves. Or with someone in great need. We feel they will lower our level of happiness, security and comfort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, that&amp;rsquo;s absolutely normal!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is normal to play it safe. It is normal to prefer the well-known and well-proven solutions instead of trying the new and unexplored ones. It is normal to avoid the unpredictable and the risky. It may even be considered normal to keep God out of the picture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is normal to follow the crowd.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jesus wouldn’t fit in that sort of normality. He was anything but normal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And as his follower, neither are you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brainwashing for You</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/brainwashing-for-you</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2014 06:59:43 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/brainwashing-for-you</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Brainwashing – the cleansing of your mind – can be something quite positive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It all depends on who is doing it, how it is done, and what the purpose is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just consider these words from an apostle:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; “Do not conform any longer to the pattern of this world, but be transformed by the renewing of your mind.” (Ro 12:2 NIV)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again our questions of interest: Who is doing it, how is it done, and what is the purpose?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My answers would be:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) You doing it&lt;br /&gt;
 2) with the help of the Spirit&lt;br /&gt;
 3) in order to reach maturity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maturity is what you see when you look at Jesus. Becoming more and more like him is God’s agenda for you. In fact, it’s an indispensable ingredient of discipleship. And as a follower of Jesus, this is what you are expected to get engaged in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With all of your heart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You do it by meditating on God’s lordship and holiness, on his words and his ways of seeing things from his perspective. It’s not a program or special activity. And it&amp;rsquo;s not something you do at certain times of the day or the week. Rather, it’s an on-going process. At all times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You do it by filling your mind with everything that comes from God’s mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This causes you to constantly evaluate your motives for what you are doing and thinking. And, not to forget, of what you are hiding. It also causes you to adapt new and better attitudes, to take new decisions, and to form new habits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You do it by casting out whatever you identify as belonging to that old Adam and fill yourself with what makes you more Jesus-like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s brainwashing at its best!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not a brutal process, but rather gentle, yet penetrating the deepest parts of your being.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Admitted, this isn’t easy. And it’s a long walk. At times it’s a struggle, probably the hardest possible for every one of us, because it&amp;rsquo;s a fight against our own fallen nature. And if it were not for the power and the wisdom of his Spirit, probably none of us would ever win that battle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, it’s also very rewarding, more than anything else we could try to accomplish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This kind of &amp;ldquo;brainwashing&amp;rdquo; isn&amp;rsquo;t only very positive, it&amp;rsquo;s a necessity for any disciple of Jesus. The results will be just glorious, like the knowledge of God and freedom from self. And along with it the peace and joy that only heaven can give.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s for you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stepping out of the Boat</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/stepping-out-of-the-boat</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2014 07:26:42 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/stepping-out-of-the-boat</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.egmontmika.com/sites/default/files/styles/large/public/Walking%20on%20water_0.png?itok=ZRWtlTjJ&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/sites/default/files/styles/large/public/Walking%20on%20water_0.png?itok=ZRWtlTjJ&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jesus didn&amp;rsquo;t promise you a safe and predictable life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many times, following him may rather feel the opposite. Like stepping out of the boat and walking on water&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What would that be like?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;Setting a Jesus-standard&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, it demands an unwavered decision for the standard you want to set. It&amp;rsquo;s not always a given choice; you’ll have to find out and understand what the Jesus-standard in your situation actually is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t expect it to be convenient or easy. Nor will it always be familiar or acknowledged by those around you. It may not even necessarily fit into your religious tradition, or correspond to any cultural or political correctness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;Doing What&amp;rsquo;s Right&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be prepared to take a risk. To act in faith, despite the facts and your previous experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t be satisfied with mediocrity. And don&amp;rsquo;t get trapped by the false security it gives you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Insist on doing what’s right, not what’s easy or common or accepted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be determined to guard your integrity and your clear conscience, thus rejecting the slightest form of corruption and any other common form of wickedness. No matter how accepted they may seem to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This may lead you to make the impossible possible. Like making peace in the midst of enmity. Or creating hope where others only see despair. Or building trust in a world of lies and broken promises.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Resulting in slowly changing people&amp;rsquo;s attitudes. Convincing them to serve others instead of exploiting them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Causing them, in turn, to step out of the boat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;Getting Involved With People&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This urges you to get involved with people. Not only with your buddies, but also with those others: the weak, the poor, the foreigners, the refugees, the odd, and other neglected and marginalised people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Giving faith to those who have no faith and hope to the hopeless, recognising their potential and investing where others have given up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stepping out of your boat&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It challenges your patience, your resilience and your grit. It tests your ability to practise forgiveness and loving-kindness at all times, even in the midst of disappointment, slander and betrayal. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sooner or later your decisions will lead to action, and eventually your actions will bear fruit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_3&#34;&gt;Looking at Jesus&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s resume: &amp;ldquo;Stepping out of the boat&amp;rdquo; outlines a way to do life that may be fundamentally different from the way many of us have learned to walk out their Christian life in the past. And the challenge may turn out to be even greater than we ever expect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, it also lets us experience far more of God’s glory than we ever might think would be possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does this scare you? Or make you feel condemned?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then don&amp;rsquo;t look at the waves. And don&amp;rsquo;t look at what you&amp;rsquo;re not capable of, or what you missed in the past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quit defending, explaining and arguing. Stop looking at yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look at Jesus!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_4&#34;&gt;Walking on Water&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only way to get involved with what God is doing today is to step out into the deep water and let him carry you on today’s current of his Spirit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, do whatever his Spirit is leading you to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t be afraid!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trust him!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Walking on water only comes to those who get out of their boat.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More than Receiving</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/more-than-receiving</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2014 17:57:23 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/more-than-receiving</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Following Jesus is more than about receiving his blessings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A major portion of contemporary church teaching and culture has its focus on the blessings of the New Covenant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And to an extent this is right. As disciples of Jesus we are living in God’s grace and are richly blessed. There is godly love, forgiveness, healing, deliverance and potentially the restoration of all areas of life available to anyone who believes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, this calls for wisdom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we make earthly blessings the primary focus of our message, we are straying from the gospel. And yet, if we make those blessings the goal of discipleship, we are dangerously jeopardizing the mission that Jesus gave us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t get me wrong, God loves to give and wants us to receive his blessings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, you cannot build a healthy relationship around just receiving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A person who does not know God will not necessarily turn to God just because of having received a miracle. And a person that goes from one miracle service to another will not automatically become a disciple by doing this even more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems that Jesus was aware of this. He didn&amp;rsquo;t take away people’s responsibility for their faith and he never used a miracle or a promise for tying them to himself or for luring them into discipleship. On the contrary, he pointed to alienation, insecurity, inconvenience, and persecution as the possible consequences of following him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You cannot bless someone into maturity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And you can&amp;rsquo;t bless someone into discipleship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a disciple of Jesus, your decision to lay down your life and submit to him must be primary. Earthly benefits are no reliable foundation for such a decision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If preachers appeal to people’s desire for security, health and comfort, they must continue to meet those needs in order to make those people continue to attend their meetings. And if God fails to meet their expectations, these people may leave and look for another &amp;ldquo;man of God&amp;rdquo;. That&amp;rsquo;s what consumers do, not disciples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ultimate goal of following Jesus is not about satisfying our earthly needs. It is to bring glory to God, no matter what our needs or our circumstances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And by his grace and by the power of his Spirit he will transform and glorify us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More than we ever can imagine or ask for.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s Your Jesus Story?</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/whats-your-jesus-story</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2014 22:20:02 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/whats-your-jesus-story</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t miss sharing your very best story!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a disciple of Jesus, you have your special story. It’s your story about that personal encounter with Jesus which caused you to respond to his call and surrender to him. It’s the story about how you “got saved”. It&amp;rsquo;s your Jesus story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It isn’t necessarily something that is perceived by your natural senses. Nevertheless, it is very real and tangible and very powerful, something that has happened at a certain point of your life between you and Jesus, and between you and the Father.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before that point you may have had some knowledge about him, facts you had learned… But now you know him in a direct and personal way as your Saviour. Now you know that Jesus is real. It’s moved from just being mental assent to a heart realisation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This knowledge combined with your personal story is your testimony. Without that testimony, you don’t really know Jesus. And without knowing him, it&amp;rsquo;s impossible to follow him. Without a testimony, you may call yourself a Christian, but you might just be participating in a good religion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what’s your story? Is it still alive? Is it still your treasure, or would it be time to dig it out again? After all, it’s one of the most powerful messages you have as a disciple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’d be a fool if you wouldn’t share it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(In case you are not at that point yet, there is a Jesus story waiting for you.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jesus Conversations</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/jesus-conversations</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2014 19:53:10 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/jesus-conversations</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The most precious, the most challenging and at the same time the most rewarding conversations I can think of are the missional conversations with someone who doesn’t know Jesus, yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are those sweet moments of grace, when heaven touches the earth, with Jesus present and someone with an open heart at the same table with you. And as you continue to meet, you can see the Spirit working conviction, redemption and transformation - a new life is about to take form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is what happened when Jesus met the Samaritan woman. And ever since has His Spirit been flowing in thousands and thousands of similar conversations, generation after generation, whenever and wherever a disciple connected with someone and shared the good news.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To see this happen is our privilege, our joy and our reward as followers of Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is what we are called to. This is what Jesus empowered us to. And this is what He is absolutely passionate about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no need to wait for a better time. According to the Lord it&amp;rsquo;s harvest time now and the harvest to be brought in is greater than ever before. Just open your eyes, it&amp;rsquo;s all around you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So be ready at all times and let the Spirit lead you. There might be one of these sweet moments of grace prepared for you today.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Only Disciples Make Disciples</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/only-disciples-make-disciples</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2014 13:58:11 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/only-disciples-make-disciples</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Institutions and offices cannot make disciples. Only disciples can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Institutions can plan and execute, administrate and produce. They can influence and direct. And they can do a good job at all this!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The typical process how institutional churches are run starts with bringing people to “church”, engaging them in church activities and programs, making them agree to certain doctrinal beliefs, and socializing them into their specific church culture, with the ultimate goal of generating members and church workers. But we have to realise that all these efforts do not necessarily make one a disciple of Jesus Christ.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Disciple making works at a much deeper level with profound implications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It starts out with God initiating something new in a person’s life, through a personal encounter, resulting in a new birth on the inside, and over time, a gradual transformation of his motives, attitudes and actions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This process is most likely facilitated by a fellow disciple one-on-one, bringing the new born under the supreme lordship of Jesus. This person accompanies the new believer for a limited time, training him and empowering him to make disciples himself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a wonderful, shared journey. At times, especially in the beginning, it can be a labour and a struggle. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Disciples are made by people who are familiar with that struggle and filled with the realisation of the victory that Jesus has won for them. They know who they are in him, and what they are able to do in his name. They know his heart and recognise his voice in their spirits. They impart to others who they are and what they are. And in and through all this they give glory to the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Institutions and offices can never achieve all this. Only disciples can! Therefore, you personally can do things that your &amp;ldquo;church&amp;rdquo; as an organisation can never do.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Being a &#34;Little Jesus&#34;</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/being-a-little-jesus</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2014 22:10:17 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/being-a-little-jesus</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The task of discipleship is to represent Jesus. This means to embody man&amp;rsquo;s redemption through Him, and to express this new reality in all aspects of life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s an individual task of every disciple as well as a corporate one, and it’s a goal as well as an ongoing, daily process. It&amp;rsquo;s the formation of the disciple into what C. S. Lewis called a “Little Jesus”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To hand this on to every human soul is the essence of the Great Commission.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hence, all our efforts as individual disciples and as a community need to match up to that task. If Jesus-likeness is not the outcome, then our spiritual giftings and ministries, our worship services, Bible studies, campaigns and mission trips are all in vain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would say, it’s not at all an easy walk. Jesus didn’t promise a comfortable journey. Man’s sinful nature is a strong force that constantly works against us from within, and self-denial has never been a popular option for anyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a cross to carry for you as a “Little Jesus”. However, the beautiful side of the coin is that his indwelling Spirit has empowered you to overcome those obstacles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is victory for you through the power of his resurrection. And with it comes true freedom, fulfillment and joy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everlasting joy!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running Ahead of Jesus</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/running-ahead-of-jesus</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2014 07:33:02 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/running-ahead-of-jesus</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a disciple, don&amp;rsquo;t run ahead of Jesus! Let him go first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That may include just about anything, but first of all it refers to our mission, to proclaim and to demonstrate his kingdom and to make disciples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jesus said, “Apart from me you can do nothing” (Jn 15:5), and I believe he meant it to be taken literally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s, indeed, quite an authoritarian statement and nothing we would like to hear! Where does this leave room for my own decisions, preferences, abilities, opinion, taste, creativity…? Who would like to live in self-denial and follow a &amp;ldquo;despot&amp;rdquo; like that?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, most of us probably won’t. That’s why we have our own interpretations of what Jesus meant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our version goes somewhat like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pray about a project.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Plan and start the project according to whatever feels good and seems reasonable, or what the budget allows, or whatever the situation requires or others expect.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ask Jesus to follow that project, bless your decision and let you succeed in whatever you do. Moreover, whenever getting in trouble, ask Jesus for help, and when getting stuck, expect him to turn up and show  the way out.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Isn&amp;rsquo;t this is a common way to put Jesus&amp;rsquo; words into practice? To us it may seem close enough to what he meant, yet, it&amp;rsquo;s far away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jesus intended to really lead us as our Lord from the beginning to the end. This means that we follow him in whatever he has prepared. He goes first and we follow him. After all, it&amp;rsquo;s all about &lt;em&gt;his&lt;/em&gt; projects, not ours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He absolutely did not mean to just walk behind us protecting our stupidities, blessing our self-centred ideas, glorifying our hubris, rescuing us from our failures, and cleaning up our messes after us!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not stupid at all to let him go first and lead, on the contrary, it is very wise and mature. And it’s never a waste of time to wait on him before starting any project. He has the right timing, we don&amp;rsquo;t. And waiting has always been one of his foremost tools to prepare our character for the task.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jesus knows what it means to follow; he had been a follower himself. He never did anything on his own, but listened to the Spirit and only did what the Father had prepared for him, right timing included.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is why we do not read about any teaching or miracle before his baptism, that is, before the Spirit started leading him. And this is why he, in turn, commanded his disciples not to do anything before Pentecost, before the Spirit would come and lead them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do we really think that we are so much better than Jesus that we could march ahead on our own? Not first wait on the Lord and listen? We might end up building our own kingdom with having to bear all the costs by ourselves and suffering the consequences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, don&amp;rsquo;t run ahead of Jesus! Wait on him, then follow.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Revival the Jesus-Way</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/revival-the-jesus-way</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2014 11:57:23 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/revival-the-jesus-way</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every revival seems to develop its own worship style and its specific methods and organisational structures for doing God’s work. And it’s quite legitimate to do so. New wine requires new wine skins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, it’s not the wine skin that makes the difference, but the wine. It’s not the worship style or a new style of preaching, teaching or praying that makes a revival. Electrically amplified sounds and flashy light effects by themselves do not add any spiritual value, neither is the presence of a large crowd in itself a sign for the Lord’s presence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not what’s happening around you, but what the Spirit does within you that leads to a revival. It’s the responsiveness of your heart that makes all the difference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, we can get highly enthusiastic over fancy new ways of worshipping the Lord and “doing church” and are happy to invite others to join us in this “new experience”. And all this is fine, as long as it enables us to open our hearts and move on into a deeper relationship with the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the Lord is far more concerned with us as a person than He is with our worship style or any of our methods or experiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After all, He has his own, unique way of reviving sinners and preparing them for his work. It’s one that works through transformation of your mind and the response of your heart. And that transformation always involves emptying, suffering, and loss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The human way to revive is to comfort, to please and to make happy. The Spirit of the Lord, however, leads to conviction, repentance and the burial of self.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Man’s way is to hand you excitement, the Lord’s way is to hand you the cross.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, do you want revival the Jesus-way?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Filling the Emptiness of Waiting</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/filling-the-emptiness-of-waiting</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2014 17:52:28 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/filling-the-emptiness-of-waiting</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Have you ever spent a day or two in an overcrowded waiting room? Tired, sweaty, hungry, and bored to death - condemned to do nothing but wait?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been there, and I hated it. Those situations can  quench your spirit and dry out your soul.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This makes me think of Nelson Mandela who spent more than 36 years of his life in a prison cell. What made this man survive mentally? What did he fill the emptiness of his imprisonment with? What did he accomplish in that cell that prepared him for presidency?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also reminds me of those thousands of imprisoned followers of Jesus, their meaningless suffering, day after day, year after year, without ending, even today at this very moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is it that makes disciples of Jesus keep their faith, hope and love in those circumstances? What enables them to bless others in the face of suffering?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously, there is a choice we can make regarding the kind of thoughts we allow our minds to be filled with, no matter what the circumstances are. Even when having been robbed of everything, we still have a responsibility for what is going on inside of us. And we can do something about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe an overcrowded waiting room isn’t that bad, after all. No matter how boring the place, I can do something about my boredom. I can remind myself of my calling and create something in my mind that changes the situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, why not try to catch someone’s attention and send a smile? Or start a conversation and share a few encouraging words? It may turn the situation round for both of us and perhaps lead up to something exciting and totally unexpected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s up to you and me to change a situation. Do we have the power to overcome? It all depends on what&amp;rsquo;s inside of us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or rather who is.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>