<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on Egmont Mika</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on Egmont Mika</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 03:01:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Faith Isn&#39;t Religion </title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/faith-isn%27t-religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/faith-isn%27t-religion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Following Jesus calls for faith. Yet, faith and religion aren’t the same. Faith isn&amp;rsquo;t religion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t confuse those two!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Typically, religion is made up of two components. There is a set of statements about what a group of people, an organization, a movement, or a society consider to be true. And there are rules, rituals and traditions to follow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Faith is beyond those things. It’s originated in another realm; it springs forth out of your spirit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Faith is your trust in God, which includes your genuine actions based on that trust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Faith is always personal. It&amp;rsquo;s yours, not your parents&amp;rsquo; or anyone else&amp;rsquo;s. And it&amp;rsquo;s never institutional. It’s rooted deep inside of you, generating qualities such as confidence, motivation, vision, courage, mental strength, patience, endurance… Faith is the ultimate motor of your actions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Religion is great as long as it provides a positive, supporting environment for your faith. At its best, it amplifies your faith.Then, religion may work out for you. However, that’s not always the case. It can also result in the opposite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Religion can quench your faith.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While faith lets you imagine what could be possible and encourages you to act on that imagination, religion reinforces the status-quo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Religion makes you fit in, not stand out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Religion is like a heavy blanket overlaid on top of your faith. As long as you accept its boundaries or don’t ever recognize that it is there, you can feel fine and enjoy whatever it offers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, for those who want to take initiative and practice an amount of freedom that is beyond those boundaries, the blanket turns into an iron ceiling, mentally and spiritually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you reach that point,  you have only two options. Adapt to the status quo and let it quench your faith, or leave.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case you are strong enough to leave, people may wonder, whether you lost your faith. Probably, rather the opposite is true. Stepping out can be the very consequence of your faith. You leave because your faith requires it. What you leave is not your faith, but just a certain temporary religious, social or cultural expression of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leaving, though, is never a convenient step. To others it may even look like a heresy or a betrayal. Or they envy you, but consider the price for themselves too high.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For you, however, that doesn’t matter anymore. For you, it has become a necessity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Disciple&#39;s Defeat and Victory</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/a-disciple%27s-defeat-and-victory/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2015 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/a-disciple%27s-defeat-and-victory/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The road of discipleship is a rocky road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it’s an all but straight and upward leading walk.
If you expected it to just take you from success to success and “from glory to glory”, you’ve probably never really tried it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In reality, walking that road doesn’t look that fantastic. Rather, it’s a slow and drawn-out process, much slower and way longer than we would imagine. And a lot messier than we would expect, filled with challenges, setbacks, failures, disappointments and unexpected turns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Typically, it seems to lead more downward than upward. And whenever you may think you have a grip on it and finally managed to secure some kind of progress, you’ll soon find out that it really wasn’t that much of a success and that you’ll have to start all over again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Lord just doesn’t follow any human standards and he has his own ways to evaluate his work and to reach his goals. He always gets there eventually, never too late, yet never too early, and never without first leading you through the deep valleys of setbacks, disappointments and hardship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s his way of refining you. It’s his curriculum for building your faith and training you for a higher cause.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is why you need to focus on him and trust him alone and not in your abilities or securities, neither let any opinion or circumstance distract or disappoint you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the outside, this road may indeed look like leading into failure. However, whatever you see and experience is never the complete truth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the middle of a setback, there is still grace for every single step and every minute of your walk. And whatever may happen to you along the way, defeat is never the last word spoken.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, that last word over your life has already been set by Jesus, long before you ever started your journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that word doesn&amp;rsquo;t spell &amp;ldquo;Victory at all times&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But FRUIT !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;comments:103f00a58cbb74d424bc69bf1165a166&#34;&gt;Comments&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;geoffrey:103f00a58cbb74d424bc69bf1165a166&#34;&gt;Geoffrey&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks, Egmont. You really pointed out many important things. The Lord just doesn&amp;rsquo;t follow any human standards. We should realise that he has his own ways, and follow them. Thanks again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t Work for God! </title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/don%27t-work-for-god/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2015 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/don%27t-work-for-god/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Don’t work &lt;em&gt;for&lt;/em&gt; the Lord! Work &lt;em&gt;with&lt;/em&gt; him!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why are there so many discouraged and burned-out pastors? Why do so many leave the ministry? Didn’t Jesus say that his burden would be light?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe ministry has become too heavy, because too much has been added by man. Too much of human ambitions and desires to influence and accomplish and control. Too much of duties, worries and fear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jesus simply expects us to follow him and make disciples. Then, naturally, we take care of each other as a family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not a problem, as long as there is no position to achieve or to keep. And no other obligations and expectations that come along with it are stealing your focus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without position, you can do as little or as much as you are able to, or have faith for, or think that you can afford. In this way, your burden is self-regulating. It never grows beyond your ability and your faith. Still, it can grow, slowly enough to enable you to grow along with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t think we need to make up a great vision or strategy or plan, just because this is what all the leadership books tell us and what every great church seems to have. It&amp;rsquo;s just a guessing anyway. And a burden. Or even a curse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And we don’t need to prove our spirituality or ability as a leader to anyone, neither to ourselves. The Lord leads by his Spirit and defines what success is, and he alone is to be honoured.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, don’t worry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t worry about &amp;ldquo;your ministry&amp;rdquo;. It&amp;rsquo;s not yours anyway, but Jesus&amp;rsquo;. And don&amp;rsquo;t submit to wrong expectations from others. Instead, find out what the Lord already has prepared for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And join in WITH him!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;comments:a8af54b7b5ff18b738968808af9fc9c3&#34;&gt;Comments&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;dan:a8af54b7b5ff18b738968808af9fc9c3&#34;&gt;Dan&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you a pastor or a church leader? The stress doesn&amp;rsquo;t come from position. It comes from people who have messages from God, who call all hours every day asking for guidance, from different institutions demanding papers and other documents for everything you as a church do. It comes from making constant decisions. It comes from good meaning folks who think you should do this or that. It comes from people trying to take control of the vision God has given to you and go a direction u know is not what God has for your church.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;egmont-mika:a8af54b7b5ff18b738968808af9fc9c3&#34;&gt;Egmont Mika&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you, Dan, for your comment. You are right that position in itself would not be a problem, but the things you mention are the very things that come along with position.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Just Do It! </title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/just-do-it%21/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2015 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/just-do-it%21/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There is no better way of teaching and learning than the hands-on training in real life situations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you want to learn how to walk, you&amp;rsquo;ll have to start walking.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you want to learn how to ride a bike, you&amp;rsquo;ll have to start biking.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you want to learn how to swim, you&amp;rsquo;ll have to start swimming.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No matter how lousy you may feel in the beginning, you&amp;rsquo;ll just have to do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the same way: If you want to learn how to make a disciple, you&amp;rsquo;ll have to start making one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More sermons will not take you there, no matter how good they are.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More Bible studies will not do it, no matter how much knowledge you get.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Neither will more prayer, no matter how much more you pray&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;if you never take the first step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no other way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just do it!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dealing with the Shameful</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/dealing-with-the-shameful/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2015 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/dealing-with-the-shameful/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;There are certain things I absolutely don’t feel happy to talk about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like telling another person how I made a fool of myself, or the number of times I reacted immaturely or arrogantly. Nor do I want to speak about the time I yelled and screamed and just couldn’t control my anger. But why should I?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why should I expose myself and admit my failures? Why bother others with my private stuff?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem is that others have seen it, and that’s embarrassing enough. Or in case nobody did, at least I know about it and feel ashamed. And of course, the Lord knows…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is there a way out?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, there is. I’ll have to talk about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Admitted, not everybody needs to know all my filth, and probably it wouldn’t be of any public interest, anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, if this thing is still bothering me, I need to talk about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I need to take a deep breath and talk to someone I trust. And contact the person I offended or let down or betrayed, not in order to explain, but to admit, regret and apologize. Then, give myself a new start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This can completely change my situation. It’s like opening a window and letting fresh air flood into my room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you in that situation?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, may I suggest that you talk about it. It isn’t always easy, yet it&amp;rsquo;s worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You won&amp;rsquo;t regret it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;comments:570519d7eb79f2aae2ba5720c1e610bb&#34;&gt;Comments&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;sara-gabrielsson:570519d7eb79f2aae2ba5720c1e610bb&#34;&gt;Sara Gabrielsson&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear Egmont, this is life-saving advice. I know from my own experience! Shame is a feeling among others and a very important one. But we need to go beyond it, because if we get stuck in shame we will run away and hide and the cause of shame will never be dealt with. If we dare to accept the shame and go beyond it and take the risk of opening up and showing ourselves as we are (with the less nice sides included) we give others a chance to give us that healing acceptance that is the key to restauration. I can&amp;rsquo;t help of thinking of pastor Robert Ekh in this context. I don&amp;rsquo;t know if that was the inspiration of your text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;egmont-mika:570519d7eb79f2aae2ba5720c1e610bb&#34;&gt;Egmont Mika&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you, Sara, for your fine commentary. You are right, this post fits very well into our situation in Uppsala, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t think of that, when I wrote it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ranking Jesus&#39; Words</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/ranking-jesus-words/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2015 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/ranking-jesus-words/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Jesus said: “Go and make disciples!” As a disciple of Jesus, how do those words rank on your list?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you think of your work, your spare time, your daily routines, and weekly obligations, including your spiritual engagements and church activities, where on that list would you place your response to Jesus’ words about making disciples?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe you have already made some disciples, or just one, or maybe none. Or maybe you are just about to make one, or planning to. Or have tried and given up, or never tried, but would like to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes our routines, habits and obligations crowd out the most important things in life. And most often our church culture with all its programs, activities and obligations keeps us from caring enough for another person and from taking the time, the effort and the sacrifice that it takes to make a disciple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, whom shall we blame?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No matter how glorious or how lousy you and I may feel about it, this is a new year and today is a new day and along with it comes the freedom for a new decision and a new start. It’s up to you and me how we respond to Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Disciple making isn’t easy for anyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, it’s possible for those who rank it high on their list.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Jesus Community</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/a-jesus-community/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2015 06:39:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/a-jesus-community/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It doesn&amp;rsquo;t take an apostle or a prophet, an appointed church leader or a church planter in order to form a simple community of disciples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My wife and I do not hold any of these offices and we never formally started a church. In fact, we never attempted to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, there has been an informal community of disciples around us ever since we opened up our family and our home and let others join us in our walk with Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This has been going on for more than 40 years and it still continues: Informal gatherings for meals, worship, bible study, prayer, counselling, working on a project, celebrations, hikes and other outdoor activities, parties, traveling&amp;hellip; and of course, personal mentoring and baptism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of these people have been living with us in our home for a year or two, or just a few months, some of them have been working with us daily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, we never had a membership list, appointed leaders, a board of elders, a budget, a constitution, a statement of faith, a list of core values, a mission statement - neither any conflict, splitting, economical problem, or burned out. And we never had any vision other than the one that Jesus gave his disciples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Probably, most people wouldn&amp;rsquo;t call it a &amp;ldquo;real church”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, there has been a constant flow of new connections, of teaching and modeling, and a building of community. In Jesus&amp;rsquo; name and under the guidance of his Spirit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of those who have been around us during these years now live in other countries and other continents. With some of them we still are in touch, per email, through social media and through actually visiting each other. Flights are cheap nowadays and make it possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This wonderful bunch of people - we may call it community - is both very little and quite large, anything between two or three and nearly a hundred.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s both a local family and a worldwide community. It&amp;rsquo;s well defined by the people who are actually meeting at a certain place and time, but it&amp;rsquo;s also hard to grasp due to its openness and flexibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not a brand, an organisation, a building, or an office, yet, it&amp;rsquo;s not just an idea in our heads either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s kept together by Jesus as Lord and by the personal relationships created by him. It&amp;rsquo;s very real and it surely is glorious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a Jesus community.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>God&#39;s Family - an Institution?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/gods-family-an-institution/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2014 06:34:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/gods-family-an-institution/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;God wants a family. Yet, man builds him an institution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you a father or a mother? Then imagine what it would feel like, if your children, as they grow up, turned your family into an institution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What would that be like?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Formal membership instead of family relations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Organized meetings and programs at special times of the week instead of common family life&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rented facilities instead of homes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Formal, elected leadership instead of parenthood&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Board meetings instead of family counsel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Democratic voting instead of common agreement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Symbolic, formalistic eating and drinking instead of real meals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tithings, and offerings whenever you come together… (The list goes on.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Honestly, as a father or a mother, would you build your family like that? And as a child or a grandchild, would you like to carry on with that kind of a heritage? Is this what you want to hand on to your own children and grandchildren?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I doubt it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How does the Lord feel about it? Is this how we best express our testimony about him who is our Father and who loves us and cares for us? Is this a true and convincing expression of his kingdom?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, I doubt it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So why are we doing this? Why are we doing this to our Father in heaven, and to each other, and to the ones we disciple, to our spiritual children?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For how long do we want to carry on? For how long do &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt;? – For sure, there is a better way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be a family!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not difficult, and it’s not far away. You can start out with two or three others and right where you are. Any follower of Jesus can take the initiative, or join someone else and contribute. No matter, if inside or outside the institution. You don&amp;rsquo;t need a building or a program or a vision or a name or a constitution or a logo or a budget or a ministry or an office&amp;hellip; And you don&amp;rsquo;t need permission.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It just takes a decision and initiation. Would that be a too hard or adventurous thing to do? What could possibly hinder you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The choice is yours and mine. And also the responsibility.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dare Letting Go!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/dare-letting-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2014 08:46:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/dare-letting-go/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Do you want to move forward? Make a positive change in your life?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But feel stuck?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you stuck in your past? Or your debts, your reputation, your failures, your self-esteem, your weight? Your salary, your negative experiences&amp;hellip;? Is your spiritual life going in circles with mere religious routines and habits?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s easy to get stuck. And it’s easy to give up and stay where you are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People spend huge amounts of time and money seeking to innovate and upgrade themselves, working to give up something, start or build something new, or change something about who they are and what they do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And ultimately fail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reaching a place where they accept failure and stop dreaming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may call it wisdom or realism and try to turn it into a virtue, but it&amp;rsquo;s killing you. Killing your dreams, your ambitions, your initiatives, your self-esteem, your joy&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; a better way. Change is possible for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Probably, change doesn&amp;rsquo;t come by just doing more of what you are already doing now. Working even harder, faster, longer, and sleeping less isn’t the answer. It simply ruins your health and your family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Neither is it a matter of style or fashion or image cultivation, or of following the trend and trying to be cool. Real, lasting and satisfying change just isn’t accomplished by polishing the surface, but rather by a change on the inside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To begin with, you’ll have to stop racing, stop pushing and stop forcing yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the same is true with the negative counterpart: Stop complaining, stop mourning, stop grieving and stop pitying yourself. Stop resigning. You&amp;rsquo;ll have to realize and acknowledge that whatever brought you to the point where you are now belongs to your past and that you are not obliged to go on with it for still another decade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And no matter how successful your walk has been in the past, maybe you&amp;rsquo;ll have to admit that it finally turned out to be a dead end road for you. It may have been good for a long time, but now it’s not working out anymore. Not good enough. Not for the next five or ten or twenty years of your life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second step would be to let go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t try to save as much of the old as possible. Admitted, there are a lot of good things worth sparing. But, as the saying goes, the good is the enemy of the best. If you want to get anywhere, you can’t keep all the old stuff and let it occupy your space and your freedom, just because it might become useful again some day in the future. You can&amp;rsquo;t save it for eternity anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There has to be some sort of inner capitulation, before you can step out into the new and unknown, the risky and the scary. And the rewarding and satisfying. Into your Father&amp;rsquo;s arms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It often takes a crisis to make us willing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And in fact, every crisis offers an opportunity for positive change. Yet, many never get all the way through to the other side where the new horizon becomes visible and the change possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They just don’t want to give up their security and their convenience. Or their illusion of who they are and what they have accomplished. Or their pride. Or fear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you desperate enough to let go?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are You Quite Normal?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/are-you-quite-normal/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2014 06:39:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/are-you-quite-normal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For being a disciple of Jesus, people may regard you as not being quite normal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what is ”normal”? In relation to what?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It could be many things, like eating breakfast in the morning, working during the day, watching the news in the evening, and sleeping at night. In that respect a disciple of Jesus wouldn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily stick out from the crowd and could be considered quite normal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, let&amp;rsquo;s think of some other more subtle aspects of life. Like for instance, our values, our fears and our desire for security.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It could be considered normal to not want to associate with certain kinds of people, like people from a different stratum of life than ours - the poor, the homeless, the foreigners, the social outcasts, those from another religious group, those who don’t share the same political views like us etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We usually don&amp;rsquo;t want to get involved with someone too different from ourselves. Or with someone in great need. We feel they will lower our level of happiness, security and comfort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, that&amp;rsquo;s absolutely normal!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is normal to play it safe. It is normal to prefer the well-known and well-proven solutions instead of trying the new and unexplored ones. It is normal to avoid the unpredictable and the risky. It may even be considered normal to keep God out of the picture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is normal to follow the crowd.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jesus wouldn’t fit in that sort of normality. He was anything but normal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And as his follower, neither are you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brainwashing for You</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/brainwashing-for-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2014 06:59:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/brainwashing-for-you/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Brainwashing – the cleansing of your mind – can be something quite positive. It all depends on who is doing it, how it is done, and what the purpose is. Just consider these words from an apostle:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; “Do not conform any longer to the pattern of this world, but be transformed by the renewing of your mind.” (Ro 12:2 NIV)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again our questions of interest: Who is doing it, how is it done, and what is the purpose? My answers would be:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) You doing it&lt;br /&gt;
2) with the help of the Spirit&lt;br /&gt;
3) to reach maturity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maturity is what you see when you look at Jesus. Becoming more and more like him is God’s agenda for you. In fact, it’s an indispensable ingredient of discipleship. And as a follower of Jesus, this is what you are expected to get engaged in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With all of your heart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You do it by meditating on God’s lordship and holiness, on his words and his ways of seeing things from his perspective. It’s not a program or special activity. And it&amp;rsquo;s not something you do at certain times of the day or the week. Rather, it’s an on-going process. At all times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You do it by filling your mind with everything that comes from God’s mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This causes you to constantly evaluate your motives for what you are doing and thinking. And, not to forget, of what you are hiding. It also causes you to adapt new and better attitudes, to take new decisions, and to form new habits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You do it by casting out whatever you identify as belonging to that old Adam and fill yourself with what makes you more Jesus-like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s brainwashing at its best!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not a brutal process, but rather gentle, yet penetrating the deepest parts of your being.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Admitted, this isn’t easy. And it’s a long walk. At times it’s a struggle, probably the hardest possible for every one of us, because it&amp;rsquo;s a fight against our own fallen nature. And if it were not for the power and the wisdom of his Spirit, probably none of us would ever win that battle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, it’s also very rewarding, more than anything else we could try to accomplish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This kind of &amp;ldquo;brainwashing&amp;rdquo; isn&amp;rsquo;t only very positive, it&amp;rsquo;s a necessity for any disciple of Jesus. The results will be just glorious, like the knowledge of God and freedom from self. And along with it the peace and joy that only heaven can give.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s for you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stepping out of the Boat</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/stepping-out-of-the-boat/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2014 07:26:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/stepping-out-of-the-boat/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Jesus didn&amp;rsquo;t promise you a safe and predictable life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many times, following him may rather feel the opposite. Like stepping out of the boat and walking on water&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What would that be like?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;setting-a-jesus-standard:9b588848469774e106d6f8ca9d86fe9d&#34;&gt;Setting a Jesus-standard&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, it demands an unwavered decision for the standard you want to set. It&amp;rsquo;s not always a given choice; you’ll have to find out and understand what the Jesus-standard in your situation actually is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t expect it to be convenient or easy. Nor will it always be familiar or acknowledged by those around you. It may not even necessarily fit into your religious tradition, or correspond to any cultural or political correctness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;doing-what-s-right:9b588848469774e106d6f8ca9d86fe9d&#34;&gt;Doing What&amp;rsquo;s Right&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be prepared to take a risk. To act in faith, despite the facts and your previous experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t be satisfied with mediocrity. And don&amp;rsquo;t get trapped by the false security it gives you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Insist on doing what’s right, not what’s easy or common or accepted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be determined to guard your integrity and your clear conscience, thus rejecting the slightest form of corruption and any other common form of wickedness. No matter how accepted they may seem to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This may lead you to make the impossible possible. Like making peace in the midst of enmity. Or creating hope where others only see despair. Or building trust in a world of lies and broken promises.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Resulting in slowly changing people&amp;rsquo;s attitudes. Convincing them to serve others instead of exploiting them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Causing them, in turn, to step out of the boat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;getting-involved-with-people:9b588848469774e106d6f8ca9d86fe9d&#34;&gt;Getting Involved With People&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This urges you to get involved with people. Not only with your buddies, but also with those others: the weak, the poor, the foreigners, the refugees, the odd, and other neglected and marginalised people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Giving faith to those who have no faith and hope to the hopeless, recognising their potential and investing where others have given up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stepping out of your boat&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It challenges your patience, your resilience and your grit. It tests your ability to practise forgiveness and loving-kindness at all times, even in the midst of disappointment, slander and betrayal. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sooner or later your decisions will lead to action, and eventually your actions will bear fruit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;looking-at-jesus:9b588848469774e106d6f8ca9d86fe9d&#34;&gt;Looking at Jesus&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s resume: &amp;ldquo;Stepping out of the boat&amp;rdquo; outlines a way to do life that may be fundamentally different from the way many of us have learned to walk out their Christian life in the past. And the challenge may turn out to be even greater than we ever expect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, it also lets us experience far more of God’s glory than we ever might think would be possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does this scare you? Or make you feel condemned?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then don&amp;rsquo;t look at the waves. And don&amp;rsquo;t look at what you&amp;rsquo;re not capable of, or what you missed in the past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quit defending, explaining and arguing. Stop looking at yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look at Jesus!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;walking-on-water:9b588848469774e106d6f8ca9d86fe9d&#34;&gt;Walking on Water&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only way to get involved with what God is doing today is to step out into the deep water and let him carry you on today’s current of his Spirit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, do whatever his Spirit is leading you to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t be afraid!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trust him!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Walking on water only comes to those who get out of their boat.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More than Receiving</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/more-than-receiving/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2014 17:57:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/more-than-receiving/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Following Jesus is more than about receiving his blessings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A major portion of contemporary church teaching and culture has its focus on the blessings of the New Covenant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And to an extent this is right. As disciples of Jesus we are living in God’s grace and are richly blessed. There is godly love, forgiveness, healing, deliverance and potentially the restoration of all areas of life available to anyone who believes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, this calls for wisdom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we make earthly blessings the primary focus of our message, we are straying from the gospel. And yet, if we make those blessings the goal of discipleship, we are dangerously jeopardizing the mission that Jesus gave us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t get me wrong, God loves to give and wants us to receive his blessings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, you cannot build a healthy relationship around just receiving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A person who does not know God will not necessarily turn to God just because of having received a miracle. And a person that goes from one miracle service to another will not automatically become a disciple by doing this even more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems that Jesus was aware of this. He didn&amp;rsquo;t take away people’s responsibility for their faith and he never used a miracle or a promise for tying them to himself or for luring them into discipleship. On the contrary, he pointed to alienation, insecurity, inconvenience, and persecution as the possible consequences of following him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You cannot bless someone into maturity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And you can&amp;rsquo;t bless someone into discipleship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a disciple of Jesus, your decision to lay down your life and submit to him must be primary. Earthly benefits are no reliable foundation for such a decision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If preachers appeal to people’s desire for security, health and comfort, they must continue to meet those needs in order to make those people continue to attend their meetings. And if God fails to meet their expectations, these people may leave and look for another &amp;ldquo;man of God&amp;rdquo;. That&amp;rsquo;s what consumers do, not disciples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ultimate goal of following Jesus is not about satisfying our earthly needs. It is to bring glory to God, no matter what our needs or our circumstances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And by his grace and by the power of his Spirit he will transform and glorify us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More than we ever can imagine or ask for.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s Your Jesus Story?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/whats-your-jesus-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2014 22:20:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/whats-your-jesus-story/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t miss sharing your very best story!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a disciple of Jesus, you have your special story. It’s your story about that personal encounter with Jesus which caused you to respond to his call and surrender to him. It’s the story about how you “got saved”. It&amp;rsquo;s your Jesus story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It isn’t necessarily something that is perceived by your natural senses. Nevertheless, it is very real and tangible and very powerful, something that has happened at a certain point of your life between you and Jesus, and between you and the Father.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before that point you may have had some knowledge about him, facts you had learned… But now you know him in a direct and personal way as your Saviour. Now you know that Jesus is real. It’s moved from just being mental assent to a heart realisation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This knowledge combined with your personal story is your testimony. Without that testimony, you don’t really know Jesus. And without knowing him, it&amp;rsquo;s impossible to follow him. Without a testimony, you may call yourself a Christian, but you might just be participating in a good religion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what’s your story? Is it still alive? Is it still your treasure, or would it be time to dig it out again? After all, it’s one of the most powerful messages you have as a disciple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’d be a fool if you wouldn’t share it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(In case you are not at that point yet, there is a Jesus story waiting for you.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jesus Conversations</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/jesus-conversations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2014 19:53:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/jesus-conversations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The most precious, the most challenging and at the same time the most rewarding conversations I can think of are the missional conversations with someone who doesn’t know Jesus, yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are those sweet moments of grace, when heaven touches the earth, with Jesus present and someone with an open heart at the same table with you. And as you continue to meet, you can see the Spirit working conviction, redemption and transformation - a new life is about to take form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is what happened when Jesus met the Samaritan woman. And ever since has His Spirit been flowing in thousands and thousands of similar conversations, generation after generation, whenever and wherever a disciple connected with someone and shared the good news.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To see this happen is our privilege, our joy and our reward as followers of Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is what we are called to. This is what Jesus empowered us to. And this is what He is absolutely passionate about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no need to wait for a better time. According to the Lord it&amp;rsquo;s harvest time now and the harvest to be brought in is greater than ever before. Just open your eyes, it&amp;rsquo;s all around you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So be ready at all times and let the Spirit lead you. There might be one of these sweet moments of grace prepared for you today.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>