<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Blogs on Egmont Mika </title>
      <generator uri="https://hugo.spf13.com">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/index.xml</link>
    <language>en-US</language>
    
    
    <updated>Wed, 21 Jan 2015 03:01:45 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ranking Jesus&#39; Words</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/ranking-jesus-words</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2015 03:01:45 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/ranking-jesus-words</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Jesus said: “Go and make disciples!” As a disciple of Jesus, how do those words rank on your list?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you think of your work, your spare time, your daily routines, and weekly obligations, including your spiritual engagements and church activities, where on that list would you place your response to Jesus’ words about making disciples?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe you have already made some disciples, or at least one, or maybe never. Or maybe you are just about to make one, or planning to. Or have tried and given up, or never tried, but would like to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes our routines, habits and obligations crowd out the most important things in life. And most often our church culture with all its programs, activities and obligations keeps us from caring enough for another person and from taking the time, the effort and the sacrifice that it takes to make a disciple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, whom shall we blame?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No matter how glorious or how lousy you and I may feel about it, this is a new year and today is a new day and along with it comes the freedom for a new decision and a new start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s up to you and me how we respond to Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Disciple making isn’t easy for anyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, it’s possible for those who rank it high on their list.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Jesus Community</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/a-jesus-community</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2015 03:01:45 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/a-jesus-community</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You don&amp;rsquo;t have to be a pastor in order to make a disciple of Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And you don&amp;rsquo;t need to be an apostle or prophet, or an appointed church leader or church planter in order to form a community of disciples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My wife and I do not hold any of these offices and we never formally “started a church”. In fact, we never attempted to.
However, there has been an informal community of disciples around us ever since we opened up our family and our home and let others join us in our walk with Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This has been going on for more than 40 years and it still continues: Informal gatherings for meals, worship, bible study, prayer, counselling, working on a project, celebrations, hikes and other outdoor activities, parties, traveling&amp;hellip; and of course, personal mentoring and baptism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of these people have been living with us in our home for a year or two, or just a few months, some of them have been working with us daily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, we never had a membership list, appointed leaders, a board of elders, a budget, a constitution, a statement of faith, a list of core values, a mission statement - neither any conflict, splitting, economical problem, or burned out. And we never had any vision other than the one that Jesus gave his disciples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Probably, most people wouldn&amp;rsquo;t call it a &amp;ldquo;real church”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, there has been a constant flow of new connections, of teaching and modeling, and a building of community. In Jesus&amp;rsquo; name and under the guidance of his Spirit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of those who have been around us during these years now live in other countries and other continents. With some of them we still are in touch, per email, through social media and through actually visiting each other. Flights are cheap nowadays and make it possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This wonderful bunch of people - we may call it community - is both very little and quite large, anything between two or three and nearly a hundred.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s both a local family and a worldwide community. It&amp;rsquo;s well defined by the people who are actually meeting at a certain place and time, but it&amp;rsquo;s also hard to grasp due to its openness and flexibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not a brand, an organisation, a building, or an office, yet, it&amp;rsquo;s not just an idea in our heads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s kept together by Jesus as Lord and by the personal relationships created by him. It&amp;rsquo;s very real and it surely is glorious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a Jesus community.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>