<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on Egmont Mika</title>
    <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on Egmont Mika</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 03:01:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://egmontmika.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Honest and Joyful</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/honest-and-joyful/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/honest-and-joyful/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Meeting people is exciting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s always interesting to listen to someone’s story. Everyone has a story worth listening to and learning from, as long they are honest and their story is true. And it’s exciting and worth both time and effort to get engaged with people who are honest about themselves and about what they do. Free from pretending.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can learn from those conversations, widen your knowledge and understanding, getting inspired. And in turn, you can encourage someone and share some of your best insights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a potential to learn and to grow for both of us when we listen to each other and talk about something that is important to us, free from fear and control and manipulation and again, free from pretending.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We need that kind of conversations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We need them in order to grow. And it’s a great joy to help each other along the way. That’s beautiful!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, is there anything more boring than listening to gossip or constant lamenting or judging comments on others? Badly enough, you can have conversations that drain your energy and make you feel empty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are your conversations like? It’s your very much choice and your responsibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let them be honest and joyful.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two Ways to Benefit from Your Enemies</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/two-ways-to-benefit-from-your-enemies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2016 06:59:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/two-ways-to-benefit-from-your-enemies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You can benefit from your enemies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indeed, you not only benefit from your families, relatives and friends and all who love you, but you can also benefit from your enemies, from those who oppose you, bother you, despise you, hate you, treat you badly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you understand this, you can turn those negative relationships into an asset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This doesn’t mean that you intentionally will have to make enemies or give people reason to hate you. However, these people happen to be around us, anyway. So why not make them part of a positive purpose!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How can you do this?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you ever asked the Lord to give you more love for the people around you, and he answered your prayer by confronting you with somebody who you really didn’t like? Or you asked the Lord to give you more patience, and he sent someone in your way who really challenged your patience?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What we learn from this is that the Lord often answers this kind of prayers, not as we may expect, by miraculously giving us wonderful feelings for these people, but by providing a training opportunity. The Lord is a master of using negative experiences for his purposes - and for our benefit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is - for our maturity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s now apply this principle to your negative relationships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may start out on a rather convenient level that most of us probably would be able to manage. Just start with one of your easier ”enemies”. This could be someone who just slightly irritates or opposes you. Maybe there is a neighbor or a colleague or a relative who would qualify in this respect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You start out by deciding to think and speak positively of this person and by doing so, you increasingly change your attitude towards that person. You also pray for him or her, not in order to change them, but to bless. Maybe you can also find a way to express your new attitude by a simple action, like a smile, an encouraging comment, a helping hand or whatever comes to your mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And remember, you don’t do it in the first place in order to turn this person round and make them love you, but for their own sake. For just loving them unconditionally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, as your second agenda, you also do it for the sake of your own maturity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By doing so, you actually may win a friend, which would be most welcome and the ultimate success. This would be your first benefit. However, there is no guarantee for that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case this doesn’t happen, you can go on loving this person anyway, and head out for your second benefit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the worst case, you may have to continue with this for the rest of your life, without ever getting a positive response; be ready for that. The other person’s negative response is not your responsibility and should not discourage you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The secret that enables you to go on is your second agenda, that is, your own maturity. And with that in mind, you always succeed, independently of your ”enemy’s” response.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By continuing to bless and love and pray, you are not only doing something in favor of this other person, but you are also improving yourself. Day by day you are proceeding towards a higher level of maturity. After some time of training, you may see your success and be ready to deal with some harder case and then succeed there, as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the outside, your one-way love may look like a hopeless endeavor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, for you who loves, it always leads to a victory.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Trust Decision</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/a-trust-decision/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2016 06:39:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/a-trust-decision/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Discipleship is a decision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don’t just slide into being a disciple of Jesus by accident. Or wake up one morning and find yourself having arrived there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It always requires a conscious decision on your behalf - your own personal decision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Neither your father nor mother, nor your buddies can do that for you. Nobody else can, but you. You don&amp;rsquo;t have to wait for anyone&amp;rsquo;s agreement, nor is there anyone else to blame for not taking that decision. And it’s not a matter of background or tradition or culture or age or education or talent or intellect or opinion…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a matter of trust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trust in Jesus and trust in his Father.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyone can make that decision, yet, this doesn’t mean that it’s easy. Before arriving at that point, you will always meet resistance. The way the resistance comes can be different from person to person and it can vary in strength.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, be sure, there will be resistance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For some of us, the resistance comes from the outside, from our families, our relatives or our buddies, from their expectations and traditions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From their fears.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It may come as light as a slight sneering comment or as heavy as a solid death threat, or as anything in between.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Resistance may also come from the inside, from our own thinking. From our distrust and doubts. Or from our pride or self-righteousness, or self-assurance&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From our own fear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The resistance has many expressions, but basically only one root: ours and others fear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, when facing the choice, it always seems easier to not follow Jesus or to postpone the decision. Or to pretend, which probably is the worst of all options. Jesus hated hypocrisy more than sin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, no matter how strong the resistance, you can at any time frankly take that decision and you’ll always find people who do the same and follow Jesus, in spite of the resistance and even under persecution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s truly a great and powerful decision with long-ranging and serious consequences, and with great and positive results for yourself as well as your surroundings. You won&amp;rsquo;t ever regret it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, it takes courage to follow Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And trust!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Destructive Faith</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/destructive-faith/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2016 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/destructive-faith/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Destruction doesn’t always have a  negative connotation. Many times it is an absolutely necessary part of the creative process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Farm lands are created by tearing down trees, better neighborhoods from slums, new life from destructive habits. They all go through destructive processes before something new could be created.  
Sometimes, new life does not appear unless and until the old has been torn down. It’s not always possible nor is it safe to be building on top of the old.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sooner or later a conflict will arise between the old and the new and you will have to make a choice. Either adjust and compromise and stay where you are, or tear down and start all over again, on a better foundation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The same is true for our spiritual life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A spiritual revival was never started by people whose hearts were still fixed in the past. It rather emerged from something new, a new revelation or a new and fresh spiritual encounter. And as a consequence, there was an overthrowing of the structures and expressions of the old.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this way, revival not only builds, but also destroys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If its destructive power scares you, you will not be able to connect to what the Lord is doing today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, at times the Lord himself is one who ”uproots”, ”tears down”, ”destroys” and ”overthrows” in order to ”build” and to ”plant”. (Jer 1:10)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Probably most of the time, it is wise to adjust, to compromise and to develop slowly. It takes time and endurance to build a house, a family, a church, a business…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, there are situations when you’ll have to jump the canyon. You can’t do it in small steps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case you are in that kind of a situation, the Lord may give you wisdom and courage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And faith to act.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Does Jesus Lead You?</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/how-does-jesus-lead-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2016 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/how-does-jesus-lead-you/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, you are a follower of Jesus?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He is your Lord and Master? And your Teacher? Then, what exactly does he teach you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No, I am not asking you what you know about him, like when and where he lived, what he did and what he said. Neither am I asking about the doctrines or morals, or whatever your church teaches about him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I’m asking is, How does he impact you? I mean, personally. Where does he rub off in your life? How does he influence your thinking, your values and attitudes? And your actions?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In short: How does he lead you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do these questions irritate you? Or do they inspire you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No matter, what your spontaneous reaction is, wouldn’t it be worth while to jot down some of your points?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Would you like to &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The challenge for you right now is to not just agree to my idea, but to actually grab a pen and a piece of paper and do it. Not just think, but write. Right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may find it hard to get started, but don’t let that hinder you. The flow will come, just you get over the initial resistance. (Writing almost always meets resistance.) And I’m sure your list will turn out far longer than expected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, choose two or three of your points and meditate a while on each one of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And let them give you clarity and strengthen you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Comments&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geoffrey:&lt;/strong&gt;
You nailed it brother, thanks for touching the sensitive conditions of our faith in JESUS.
This makes me stand still and find back the true meaning of my calling in him.
Thanks again.
Geoff&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Much Are Your Ideas Worth?</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/how%20much%20worth%20are%20your%20ideas/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2016 06:39:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/how%20much%20worth%20are%20your%20ideas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Great ideas are fun!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Great ideas sound good and make you feel good. Great ideas always find their listeners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, an idea is quite irrelevant as long as it isn’t tested.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The testing makes all the difference. It separates the achiever from the mere dreamer. The testing is the real hard part.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Probably, one thing the testing shows is that your great idea isn’t really that great. Others had the same idea before you and didn’t find it worth the trouble to make it work out. Or they gave it some tries and failed. You should know about that, before you start working and investing your time and energy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This requires honesty, good judgement and decidedness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondly, the testing probably shows that your great idea will not be accomplished as easily and fast as you thought. You’ll have to admit that before you can make a long-term plan and prepare yourself for the process that is required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On top of honesty, good judgement and decidedness, this requires patience and persistence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover, the testing will probably show that you are not as smart as you thought. You’ll have to admit even that, before you are willing to learn more, understand more, develop some more skills and start asking for help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This requires humility and dedication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, the testing will possibly show that your great idea doesn’t work out the way you thought. At this point, your idea may look like a failure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After this insight, your real work begins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From now on, your idea requires faith.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The world doesn’t need more people announcing a thousand bright ideas. What we need is someone who is willing to stick to one idea and test it, develop it, and refine it, and never give up - until it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alas! You can preach as much as you want, yet, making a disciple for Jesus is quite a different story!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Much Is Half a Promise Worth?</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/how-much-worth-is-half-a-promise/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2016 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/how-much-worth-is-half-a-promise/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you are hungry, half a hamburger is better than nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you need  to finance a project, raising only half of the money is better than no money at all.
If you’re expecting a thousand people to read your article and only five hundred actually read it, this is still better than none.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many times, half is better than nothing. But not always. What about half a promise?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you ask a baby sitter to come over…&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you invite friends for dinner…&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you need a partner for your project…&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you want to marry…&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…and the answer you get never surpasses a ”maybe”, I would call this giving half a promise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Half a promise can be worse than no promise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a ”no”, you still had the choice of asking someone else, but with a ”maybe” you are stuck. You don’t get anywhere, and things can get even worse. Like, when &amp;ldquo;promising&amp;rdquo; a beach vacation to your family, or &amp;ldquo;agreeing&amp;rdquo; to engage in a project, or &amp;ldquo;promising&amp;rdquo; a life-long marriage - and never getting beyond a &amp;ldquo;maybe&amp;rdquo;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In these cases, half a promise can end in a sheer disaster for you and for whoever partners with you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The same is true for our decision to follow Jesus. He expects us to give him a clear ”yes” or ”no”, not a ”maybe”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And pretending would be even worse than that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s good for you and me to make up our minds and know what we want and what we don’t want to engage in. And it’s a blessing for everyone around us when we are able give them a clear ”yes” or ”no”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you can’t give a wholehearted promise, it’s probably better not to give any.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>For Those Who Care</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/for-those-who-care/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2015 06:39:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/for-those-who-care/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Jesus called us to make disciples. And making a disciple comes with a price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It costs you your time, energy, and money. It calls for patience, wisdom and endurance. It&amp;rsquo;s a long-term commitment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you may wonder: Am I really prepared for this? Is it possible for me to give more time, energy, and money? Am I patient enough, wise enough, and committed enough?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As to time, energy and money, the answer is pretty simple: You already have enough. Jesus didn&amp;rsquo;t have more. Weed out those projects and activities that you have given undue importance to. You may want to reevaluate your priorities. That should be possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or, it should be possible for those who really care.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As to patience, endurance, wisdom and commitment, these are a little harder to learn and to improve. Yet, there is no use waiting for it to happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You learn these things by doing something that requires practicing those very qualities. Try to find a challenging task. Make a decision and then stick to it, no matter how strong the resistance and no matter how often you fail. You can improve along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Probably, most of us already have one or a few areas where we can get that kind of training. There may be an education that needs to be finished, a project to be completed, a language to be learnt, a book to be written, a house to be renovated…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And why not, a disciple to be made?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, you can start with your mission right away. Start making a disciple, and then improve along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is always one first little step you can take, little enough to match your faith and your resources. You can take that step and stick to it. From there, you will know what to do next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Isn’t this exactly what young parents do? None of us fathers and mothers are really prepared for raising children the day we bring home our first baby. That day we get a kick-start. From there we go on, day by day and night by night and learn patience, endurance, wisdom and improve our commitment along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not always easy to be a parent, and for some of us it’s a real struggle. However, it works out somehow, against all odds, and in spite of all the mistakes we make.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is what making a disciple is very much alike. It’s costly and it isn’t always easy, yet…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s possible for those who really care.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s Your Response to Terror?</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/how-do-you-respond-to-terror/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2015 06:39:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/how-do-you-respond-to-terror/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Paris, November 13th, 2015 !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overwhelmed and horrified by what happened that night, I asked myself, &lt;em&gt;What is my response to all those terror attacks in recent years, not only in the Middle East and in places “far away”, but also increasingly in Europe?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Will the horror stay with me and eventually leave me in a constant state of fear? Will it affect my attitude towards the world and the people around me, towards Muslims in general as well as towards my Muslim friends, colleagues, students and neighbours?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And will it possibly lead me to a reaction that ultimately feeds into a culture of resentment, distrust and fear?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing is for sure, if I let fear grip me, then the attacks have accomplished their purpose in me and the terrorists have won the victory!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This shall never happen!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, there is another possible response.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘Eagles of Death Metal’, the band that played at Bataclan that night, made the following statement, issued in &lt;em&gt;The Guardian&lt;/em&gt; on November 18th:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Although bonded in grief with the victims, the fans, the families, the citizens of Paris, and all those affected by terrorism, we are proud to stand together, with our new family, now united by a common goal of love and compassion.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This view opens up for a better response and reminds me of the mission we have as followers of Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You and I may not be able to stop terrorism and solve all the problems connected to it. However, we can remain the masters of our minds and our faith, guard our feelings and attitudes, care for each other, build trust relationships and cultivate community - Muslims included.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overcoming fear by practicing love and true humanity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taking action for a better world.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Walking the Bumpy Road</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/walking-the-bumpy-road/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2015 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/walking-the-bumpy-road/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are you looking for a safe and comfortable road to travel on?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, following Jesus might not be the right choice for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jesus never invited anyone to a safe journey. Neither did his Father. The Bible is filled with stories about men and women who knew God and faithfully followed him on a rather bumpy road with many potholes, detours and dangers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just think of Abraham, Joseph, Moses, Elijah, David, Isaiah, Jeremiah, Jesus, Paul… Their lives were characterized by dangers, hardship, risks, threats, agonies and persecution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jesus was one of them, and he didn’t promise his followers anything different from what he experienced. Least of all security and comfort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, this seems to be what millions of his followers daily pray for and expect for their lives. And churches do their best to make Christianity appear a pleasant experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And in case we let Sunday morning performances be the foremost expression of what it means to follow Jesus, this is what we communicate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, by filtering out the hardship, the pain, the struggle, the risks, the drop-backs, the sweat and the dirt of everyday life, we may end up reducing discipleship to a nice Sunday morning smile. That kind of religion will never stand the test of credibility. Neither the test of authenticity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, if we intentionally face those trials, the hardship and the discomfort, and not only try but actually overcome by strengthening our faith, putting our spiritual weapons into practice and standing side by side as brothers and sisters, trusting the Lord to give us a victory, we make an astonishing discovery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We then find out that He is with us right there walking alongside with us, leading us through every hardship and towards our destiny. And we discover that this bumpy and tiresome road we are walking on actually is the road of our calling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The road where His grace becomes most visible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What a blessing!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your Great Work</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/your-great-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2015 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/your-great-work/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Great work doesn’t come out of nowhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it’s not only a privilege for the talented.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Usually great work results from someone working hard and trying over and over again, failing included - many times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover, it&amp;rsquo;s risky.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s risky before you get started, and it&amp;rsquo;s risky all the way through until it&amp;rsquo;s finished. It can cost you everything; your time, your sleep, your comfort, your money, your reputation - and your pride.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Great work makes you humble.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Great work isn’t always recognized as such from the beginning. And you often don&amp;rsquo;t see its greatness during the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those who don’t have the faith, it really doesn’t look that great. They just can’t imagine that you are building a cathedral. What they see is the sand you are shoveling; and they notice the dirt, the sweat and the pain it causes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Raising children is very much like that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Changing diapers just doesn&amp;rsquo;t feel that glorious. And coping with a teenager’s mood doesn’t always look like a great success. Nevertheless, it&amp;rsquo;s great work! No matter what you feel during the process and no matter how many times you fail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s great, as long as you carry on faithfully, day by day, year in year out. The time will come when you and even others will see the result of your labour. One day your cathedral will be completed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, raising children is far greater than building a cathedral.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feeling Like a Failure?</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/feeling-like-a-failure/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2015 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/feeling-like-a-failure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Having failed isn&amp;rsquo;t the same as feeling like a failure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feeling like a failure can be much worse than the actual failure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A failure in itself is just an event, not a feeling. It&amp;rsquo;s something specific that happened to you at a specific time in a specific place. Like you didn’t pass the test, couldn’t keep your promise, missed your flight, lost your credit card, or made a foolish comment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A failure can be dealt with successfully in basically three ways&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can repair the damage. There is no use crying over spilt milk. You know what to do, so just do it. Often a simple excuse is good enough.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can’t repair the damage, but you definitely can learn from it. Notorious late comers can actually stop blaming the circumstances and instead admit their failure, go to the bottom of their issue and take practical steps to change their habit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can ignore it. If you just missed an opportunity, there isn’t much that can be done. No use of grieving. It may be emotionally challenging and you may have to pay a price, but so what? You must leave it behind you and carry on.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not always easy to handle a failure, but most failures can be dealt with in a rational way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s much harder to cope with feelings. Feelings can be irrational.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feeling like a failure has very little to do with actually failing. You can fail a thousand times without necessarily feeling like a failure. On the other hand, you can even feel like a failure in the face of obvious success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feeling like a failure isn’t based on what has occurred, but on our thinking. On the story we tell ourselves or what others tell us about ourselves. Such a story works like a prophecy. Once you believe it, you will try to prove it and find evidence for it. For sure, you will always find what you are looking for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you feel discriminated, neglected, looked down at, hated or felt sorry for, rest assured they have their origin in patterns of thoughts… in your story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, if you want to protect yourself and stop feeling like a failure, there are a few essential steps you can take:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Stop meditating on your false story. Throw it out of your mind and refuse to let it settle there again, whenever those thoughts show up. Remember that you are the master of your mind.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Stop engaging with the false assumption that in order to stop feeling like a failure you’ll have to succeed. You don&amp;rsquo;t. You can get rid of that feeling without a single success.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Instead, start meditating on another story, based on the story that Jesus gave us: ”You are a child of God, beautifully made, loved, forgiven and accepted, created for a divine purpose, destined to be a blessing…&amp;rdquo; Let your Father in heaven determine who you are and what you are.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you choose the latter and start building your faith on His story, for sure, your feelings will follow and you will be healed and restored.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; The decision is yours.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your Precious Failures</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/your-precious-failures/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2015 03:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/your-precious-failures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nobody likes failures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, failures are more precious than most of us are inclined to think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, they can become stepping stones towards our final success. Don’t get me wrong, a failure really is a failure, not a success. It&amp;rsquo;s ugly, discouraging, accusing, threatening, judging! However&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A failure doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to be the final word spoken. The crucial question is, what do you do with it? What comes next?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think of Thomas Edison. Holding as many as 1093 patents in the United States, and in addition many patents in the United Kingdom, France, and Germany, he probably was one of the most prolific inventors of all times. Edison became famous not only for the widespread impact of his inventions, but also for his unbroken decisiveness to never give up. It is said that before succeeding with his first well-functioning light bulb in 1879, he went through around 2000 failures. When during the time of his endless struggles being asked, why he wouldn’t give up such a meaningless endeavor, he gave his well-known answer. ”It’s not a failure at all”, he said, ”I just found 2000 ways of how not to make a light bulb”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inventions are made when someone thinks outside the box and tries to accomplish something that others call impossible, or at least meaningless, and uses every failure as a stepping stone for still another try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, our problem is that we are stuck inside the box and all we can do is think inside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, how do you manage to think on the outside? What then makes individuals finally free themselves from the bonds of the well-known and secure paths of thought, risk a failure and jump the leap? How do you accomplish such a feat?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many times, it’s through a deep crisis caused by a failure. Sometimes, it’s out of pure desperation. You are stuck and can&amp;rsquo;t see any way out. You hit the bottom and have nothing to lose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is when you are ready to stretch beyond what seems possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seen that way, failures are the condition in which creativity is ignited. They are the soil out of which success springs forth, but only for those who stop mourning and lamenting and decide to try again and go on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Judas didn’t have to end up in a tragedy. That was his own decision, his own self-made judgement. As Jesus restored Peter, I am sure he was ready to even forgive Judas and open up a new life for him, a life of peace and freedom way beyond his failure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how do you think about your recent failure? What’s your decision? Are you ready to welcome and embrace it and learn from it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And open a new and unexpected door.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Geoffrey:&lt;/em&gt;  Thank you Egmont! This is true and I have been in failures many times, and I have seen the hand of God in the end of it. The worst part was when I was laughed at, but I was deeply convicted that God my heavenly father will turn it up for his glory. Thanks again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reply:&lt;/em&gt; Thank you, Geoff! You are right. The Lord is a master of turning things round. We just need to wait.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Full-Time, Part-Time or Spare-Time Ministry?</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/full-time-half-time-or-spare-time-ministry/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 06:39:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/full-time-half-time-or-spare-time-ministry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a disciple of Jesus, do you have a full-time or a part-time ministry?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or is yours &amp;ldquo;only&amp;rdquo; spare-time?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No matter what your answer is, following Jesus is neither one. If you are his disciple, you are what you are twenty-four hours a day, seven days a week. That’s neither full-time nor part-time nor spare-time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;all-the-time!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason for that? Discipleship isn’t based on a service, a duty or a program. It&amp;rsquo;s neither an employment nor a hobby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Discipleship is a relationship - your relationship with Jesus. And as his disciple you are a child of God; that’s a position, and again a relationship. Everything you do is done within that relationship and can be seen as an expression of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, churches and denominations offer employments, full-time or part-time. And they engage volunteers in their spare-time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All these workers have their specific responsibilities and duties. They follow the instructions, meet people&amp;rsquo;s needs, and try to make everyone happy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On top of that, they probably have an idea of listening to the Lord and try to follow him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doing both of these doesn&amp;rsquo;t always work out so well. Following Jesus and fulfilling the requirements for an employee or volunteer aren’t automatically the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following Jesus isn&amp;rsquo;t the same as building an organization or pleasing the people around you. If it works out for you, that&amp;rsquo;s fine. As long as it lasts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At worst, you may feel like having to serve two masters, which can lead to conflict, frustration and stress, and sometimes even burn-out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jesus worked hard, yet never seemed to get any of these symptoms. Is it, because he only served one master and never submitted to people’s expectations?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus, he was free to wholeheartedly listen to the Spirit and obey the One who had sent him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any-time. All-the-time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are You a Spiritual Leader?</title>
      <link>http://egmontmika.com/blog/are-you-a-spiritual-leader/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2015 06:39:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://egmontmika.com/blog/are-you-a-spiritual-leader/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Following Jesus rubs off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a disciple of Jesus, you influence your environment and the people around you. Discipleship often develops into leadership.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a different kind of leadership, though. Different from what most people would expect. Often lacking the most typical characteristics that you usually associate with leadership, like power, position, title, status, money, popularity, image, good looks, high IQ, education, or whatever else impresses on people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s an up-side-down leadership. It&amp;rsquo;s built on servanthood and qualities like humility, honesty and integrity. Like trustworthiness, reliability and morality. And faithfulness and wisdom. And love. And the fear of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In short, it&amp;rsquo;s spiritual leadership.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;True spiritual leadership is based on discipleship, that is, on being a disciple of Jesus. Discipleship comes first, spiritual leadership emerges from there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can’t lead another person along a spiritual path without first having walked that path yourself. And you can’t lead that person into a fruitful disciple relationship without being a disciple yourself. The quality of your leadership depends uttermost on the quality of your discipleship. You cannot lead a disciple beyond your own level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, are you looking for a spiritual leader? Then, have a closer look at his or her discipleship. Leaders in formal positions are not necessarily fruitful disciples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, fruitful disciples can naturally develop into spiritual leaders, independently of any formal position.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might be one of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;comments:4de4065ea1f1f9d60973d0fdd5cda222&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Comments&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amelie&lt;/strong&gt; - LOVE IT!
I always thought I needed more of the typical leadership qualities in order to be a great leader, but I found out that there are people around me that I can disciple. That makes being a leader so easy and it comes so natural.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Susan&lt;/strong&gt; - I am begining to see this more and more. Strange that it should take so long for me to arrive at this conclusion&amp;hellip;Truly desire to walk this path with any who sincerely wants to join. :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>